<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch4.html#ch4">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__33">4</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__33">How to Give Advice</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__33">H</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__33">AVING</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" xml:space="preserve" Tag="__33"> EXAMINED</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" xml:space="preserve" Tag="__33"> THE FIRST</Run>
          <Run Tag="__33"> of the three skills (earning trust, giving advice effectively, and building relationships), we now turn to the second skill: advice giving.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">Many professionals approach the task of giving advice as if it were an objective, rational exercise based on their technical knowledge and expertise. But advice giving is almost never an exclusively logical process. Rather, it is almost always an emotional &#x201C;duet,&#x201D; played between the advice giver and the client. If you can&#x2019;t learn to recognize, deal with, and respond to client emotions, you will never be an effective advisor.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__33">Early in David&#x2019;s career, the management team of a large professional firm asked his opinion about how they were conducting their affairs. He responded with a very direct and candid answer. &#x201C;Here are the things you are messing up, and this is what you should have been doing!&#x201D; To his surprise, David was fired for being a disruptive influence. This was hard to understand, since he knew (and knew that </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">they</Run>
          <Run Tag="__33"> knew) that he was correct in his diagnosis and prescriptions.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__33">Eventually, David learned the obvious lesson. It is not enough for a professional to be </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">right</Run>
          <Run Tag="__33">: An advisor&#x2019;s job is to be </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">helpful</Run>
          <Run Tag="__33">. David had to develop the skill of telling clients they were wrong in a way that they would thank him for giving helpful advice! He had to &#x201C;earn the right&#x201D; to be critical. Proving to someone that they are wrong may be intellectually satisfying, but it is not productive for either the client or the advisor.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__33">Critiquing one&#x2019;s clients is, </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">by definition</Run>
          <Run Tag="__33">, a part of every professional&#x2019;s job. Suggestions on how to improve </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">always</Run>
          <Run Tag="__33"> carry the implied critique that all is not being done well at the moment. Yet it is the person hiring you who is often responsible for the current state of affairs.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">Lawyers are usually retained by the in-house general counsel; accountants by the chief financial officer; marketing, public relations, and communications consultants by the vice president of marketing; and actuaries by the head of human resources or the pension officer. More often than not, the person hiring you is a key player in the issues you are being asked to address. The advisor therefore needs to tread carefully!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">Because of this, the diagnosis and solution of a client problem can never be performed without considering the sensitivities, emotions, and politics of the client situation. No matter how technical one&#x2019;s field or discipline, the act of giving advice is crucially dependent on a deep understanding of the personalities involved, and on the ability to adapt the advice-giving process to the specific individuals involved.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__33">The Client&#x2019;s Perspective</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__33">To understand some of the emotions surrounding the client&#x2019;s use of professionals, think of the personal risks (reputation, promotion opportunities, bonuses, perhaps even one&#x2019;s career) that go along with the responsibility for choosing (and working with) any outside provider for a risky or expensive corporate matter. How would you like to be known as the person to blame if the corporate headquarters designed by the architect (that </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__33">you</Run>
          <Run Tag="__33"> chose) didn&#x2019;t work out? If the major lawsuit was lost? If the new marketing campaign failed to deliver the goods?</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__34">Viewed in this light, the client has every right to enter the process of using an outsider in a high state of anxiety. What&#x2019;s worse, the client&#x2019;s inevitable caution and trepidation are reinforced by the fact that outside professionals often see complications in a project the client doesn&#x2019;t see. In fact, it is an essential part of the professional&#x2019;s craft to reveal nuances, problems, barriers, and issues of which the client is unaware. If these are not conveyed with tact and skill, the client could easily believe (however unfairly) that, rather than relieving fears and being helpful, the professional is creating complications.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__34">There are other emotional issues usually present as well. In the normal course of their business lives, client executives are people of accomplishment, authority, and respect within their organization. When hiring an advisor, they are forced to place their affairs for an uncertain period of time (and cost) into the hands of a practitioner of an impenetrable art, who often uses indecipherable jargon and engages in mysterious and unexplained (but probably expensive) activities. Predictably, the average client experiences unwelcome feelings of dependency or loss of control.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__34">What clients frequently want is someone who will take away their worries and absorb all their hassles. Yet all too often, they encounter professionals who add to their worries and create extra headaches, forcing them to confront things they would prefer to ignore. (&#x201C;Doctor, I came to you about my sore feet, and you are giving me grief about my weight. Can&#x2019;t you just treat my feet and leave me alone about my weight?&#x201D;) Since clients are often anxious and uncertain, they are, above all, looking for someone who will provide reassurance, calm their fears, and inspire confidence.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__34">It can take some time for many advisors to realize that it is a central part of their profession to develop these interpersonal skills. Certainly no one ever teaches them to us in our training, either in school or inside the typical professional firm.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__34">A Chat with Mom or Dad</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__34">Essential to being an effective advisor is having a good understanding of one&#x2019;s role. This is illustrated by a lawyer friend of ours, who once said:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__34">&#x201C;Sometimes I feel like I&#x2019;m explaining things to a child. My client can&#x2019;t seem to grasp even the basic logic of what I&#x2019;m trying to convey. I feel like saying, &#x2018;Shut up. Just accept what I&#x2019;m telling you! I&#x2019;m the expert here!&#x2019; &#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__34">What makes this lawyer&#x2019;s comments so understandable is that, in many advisory relationships, the client is untrained in the professional&#x2019;s specialty, while the professional may have seen the client&#x2019;s problem (or variants of it) many times before. There is thus an almost constant threat of coming across to the client as patronizing, pompous, and arrogant.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">It is understandable why advisors can feel this way, and it is equally clear why clients resent it. After all, when I&#x2019;m the client, I&#x2019;m the one in charge. If I don&#x2019;t understand what you are saying, then maybe the problem is you, not me.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__35">Maybe you don&#x2019;t know how to convey what you know and understand to a lay person. </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">Of course</Run>
          <Run Tag="__35"> I don&#x2019;t know your field; that&#x2019;s why I hired you! </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">Explain</Run>
          <Run Tag="__35"> it to me in language I can understand. Help me get it! Your job is not just to assert conclusions, but to help me </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">understand</Run>
          <Run Tag="__35"> why your recommended course of action makes sense. Give me reasons, not just instructions!</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">Although advising clients sometimes feels like explaining things to a child, the secret to becoming a good advisor is to do exactly the opposite.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">We should act as if we are trying to advise our mother or father. If we are trying to convince Mom or Dad to do something, we are more likely to find the right words to convey our point so that it comes across with great respect, so that any implied critique is softened as much as possible.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__35">This doesn&#x2019;t mean avoiding the issue, or rolling over and playing dead to whatever they say. It may be that what they are doing is disrupting the rest of the family, or is against their own interests. We </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">must</Run>
          <Run Tag="__35"> find a way to get our point across. Nevertheless, we must enter the encounter with the right attitude and with careful attention to phrasing.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__35">When talking to a family member or a client, a primary task is to diffuse defensiveness (which, it should be noted, is </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">always</Run>
          <Run Tag="__35"> present). If we are to influence a parent or a client, we must find a way to prove we are trying to help, not to criticize.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">It should be clear that we don&#x2019;t just tell Mom or Dad what to do (even if they ask us directly). Instead, we focus less on the advice (or conclusion) itself and more on creating a dialogue or conversation that helps them see the issue from a new perspective.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">&#x201C;You&#x2019;ve every right to do that, Dad, but Sister has a few extra burdens because of what&#x2019;s happening. Can you help ease the pressure on her? Is there anything we could do to help her?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">A business equivalent to this might be:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__35">&#x201C;That&#x2019;s a sensible decision. Before we settle on it, let&#x2019;s think through some of the implications. It&#x2019;s very likely that the dealers will be unhappy, and we need their cooperation in order to succeed. Is there some way to accommodate their needs so that we can keep them enthusiastically supporting the new plan?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__36">Finding the Right Words</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__36">Excellence in advice giving requires not only the right attitude, but also a careful attention to language. There are always a number of ways of expressing the same thought, each of which differs in how it is received by the listener. Saying &#x201C;You&#x2019;ve got to do X,&#x201D; even when correct, is very likely to evoke emotional resistance. No one likes to be told that they </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__36">must</Run>
          <Run Tag="__36"> do anything (even when they do).</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__36">It is usually better to say something like:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__36">&#x201C;Let&#x2019;s go through the options together. These are the ones I see. Can you think of anything else that we should consider? Now let&#x2019;s go through the pro&#x2019;s and con&#x2019;s of each course of action. Based on those pros and cons, action X seems the most likely to work, doesn&#x2019;t it? Or can you think of a better solution?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__36">If the client doesn&#x2019;t want to do X, the conversation is still alive. If you&#x2019;ve said &#x201C;You&#x2019;ve got to do X&#x201D; and the client says &#x201C;No, I don&#x2019;t,&#x201D; you&#x2019;ve nowhere to go. Your effectiveness as an advisor has just been lost, and you have placed yourself and the client on opposite sides. The odds are that what will follow will be an argument, not a discussion. (Naturally, the precise phrasing we have offered above is not the key point. You must find the words that work for you.)</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__36">Numerous other examples of &#x201C;hard&#x201D; and &#x201C;soft&#x201D; phrasing can be given. Take something as simple as, &#x201C;What are your problems?&#x201D; Seemingly a simple question, this can easily be taken as confrontational and challenging. A good substitute might be, &#x201C;What is most in need of improvement?&#x201D; As a quick rule of thumb, it is usually better to try to turn assertions into questions. Instead of saying, &#x201C;This is the best solution,&#x201D; try the following: &#x201C;My other clients usually do X for the following reasons. Do you think that reasoning applies here?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__36">Many years ago, when David taught mathematical statistics, he was at the front of the class, writing on the blackboard. Pausing from time to time, he asked the students, &#x201C;Did everyone understand that?&#x201D; There was silence in the room, and he therefore assumed he was doing just fine as a teacher. At examination time, however, everybody failed the test. He had failed as a teacher! He was frustrated because he thought he had created many opportunities to check for his clients&#x2019; (or students&#x2019;) understanding.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__36">A colleague pointed out that his attitude was fine, but his skills were weak. By asking, &#x201C;Did everyone understand that?&#x201D; he was creating an atmosphere in which students would have to confess weakness if they said no. His friend recommended that he change his question to &#x201C;Have </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__36">I</Run>
          <Run Tag="__36"> made myself clear here?&#x201D;</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__36">Phrased that way, it was easier for someone to say, &#x201C;No, you haven&#x2019;t.&#x201D; Even if this was more challenging to David&#x2019;s ego, it gave him the chance to ensure that his points were being understood. Another way to deal with this situation would be to ask, &#x201C;Would you like to stay on this point or move on to the next topic?&#x201D; This is a neutral way of letting students (clients) express confusion about a topic (or lack of acceptance) without threatening their ego or embarrassing them. The principle here is that the successful advisor assumes responsibility for the proper mutual understanding.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__37">All this shows that we aren&#x2019;t always aware of how we are coming across in our client conversations. We know what we intend to convey, but we do not always know how we are being received.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__37">One device to help in this skill-building process is to rehearse a client conversation, with a friend or colleague playing the role of client. The simple act of watching another in conversation immediately reveals opportunities to spot those occasions where one could have phrased things differently to avoid the perception of being pompous, assertive, threatening, or unclear. And if we miss them, the other person can likely point them out.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__37">If, in addition, you videotape the rehearsal, you get yet another opportunity for perspective. When we listen to others or see ourselves on video, the areas for improvement are usually blatantly clear. As the poet Robert Burns noted, there is no greater benefit than &#x201C;to see ourselves as others see us.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__37">A Teacher&#x2019;s Skills</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__37">In many ways, advisory skills are similar to those of great teaching. A teacher&#x2019;s task is to help a student get from point A (what they know, understand, and believe now) to point B (an advanced state of deeper understanding and knowledge). It is poor teaching for the professor to stand at the front of the class and say, &#x201C;B is the right answer!&#x201D; (As the old joke goes, a lecture is the fastest means known for getting ideas from the notes of the teacher into the notes of the student without passing through the minds of either.)</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__37">A teacher needs two skills to be really effective. First, the teacher must have a good understanding of point A: Where is the student (or client) starting from? What does he or she understand now? What do they believe and why do they believe it? For what messages are they ready? What are they doing now and why are they doing it that way? This understanding of one&#x2019;s student (or client) can only come from doing a lot of questioning and listening, saving one&#x2019;s reactions until later in the teaching (or advisory) process.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__37">Having understood point A, the teacher cannot jump straight to a discussion of B, the end point. The second required skill is to develop a step-by-step reasoning process that takes the student/client on a journey of discovery. The goal here is to influence the student/client&#x2019;s understanding so that, eventually, the student/client says, &#x201C;You know, on reflection, I think B is a better answer,&#x201D; to which the teacher/advisor can respond, &#x201C;OK, that&#x2019;s what we&#x2019;ll do!&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__37">This process is, of course, what is usually termed </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__37">Socratic teaching</Run>
          <Run Tag="__37">. It is mostly accomplished through questions such as the following:</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Disc" Margin="64,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14" Tag="__37">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__37">Why do you think we have this problem?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__37">What options do we have for doing things differently?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__37">What advantages do you foresee for the different options?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__37">How do you think the relevant players would react if we did that?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__37">How do you suggest we deal with the following adverse consequences of such an action?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__38">Other people have encountered the following difficulties when they tried that. What can we do to prevent such things occurring?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__38">What benefits might come if we tried the following approach?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__38">Socratic reasoning does take a great deal of patience. It is normal for the teacher to feel an almost overwhelming temptation to scream out, &#x201C;But the answer is clear: we should do B! Listen to me!&#x201D; This would be entirely intellectually correct as an answer, but a complete failure in advice giving.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__38">Dealing with Client Politics</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__38">Among other things, effective advice giving requires an ability to suppress one&#x2019;s own ego and emotional needs. The most effective way to influence a client is to help the person feel that the solution was (to a large extent) his or her idea, or at the very least, his or her decision.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__38">One way to do this is to help the client understand all the available options by conducting a thorough exploration of advantages, disadvantages, risks, and costs. You can then gently guide the client to the preferred solution. Notice that this usually means avoiding the temptation to take a stand too early in the process. An advisor&#x2019;s role is to be an expert guide in the process of reasoning through the problem. Our ability to be accepted as trustworthy guides can be damaged if our client believes we have already reached our own inflexible conclusion.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__38">A good process for the advisor to follow is:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Decimal" Margin="48,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__38">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__38">Give them their options</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__38">Give them an education about the options (including enough discussion for them to consider each option in depth)</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__38">Give them a recommendation</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__38">Let them choose</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__38">Some clients may want you to choose for them. But that, too, is their choice. If they ask you to choose, a tactful way to respond to this is to say, &#x201C;If this were my business or my money, I would do X.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__38">In extreme cases, your client might choose a path that you do not care to be associated with, and you may elect to withdraw. As painful as this might be, it is better than continuing to try to force your conclusion on the client. If your persuasive skills fail to work, and you can&#x2019;t live with what the client plans to do, then there is no other choice.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__38">The advisor&#x2019;s role as a guide through the reasoning process becomes even more critical when dealing with committees, groups, or other situations where more than one person is involved in the decision. In such cases, one must learn how to assist one&#x2019;s client by surfacing and clarifying different points of view, and by building consensus among the client personnel. Rarely does an advisor have only one person as the client. Even if you are reporting to the CEO, it is usually the case that others must be &#x201C;won over&#x201D; in order for any action to take place.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__39">Even powerful decision makers such as CEOs tend to involve their chief financial officer, their general counsel, or other corporate officers before a final decision is reached. Not surprisingly, since these people represent different constituencies, they each bring a different perspective to the problem you have been asked to help with. It follows that client politics are unavoidable in any advisory situation. If you can&#x2019;t deal with client politics, you cannot be an effective advisor.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__39">Accordingly, all advisors must learn the skills and methodologies for bringing the different players &#x201C;on board.&#x201D; For example, in many (if not most) advisory situations, clients schedule meetings involving a number of important players, each (usually) with his or her own agenda. Some advisors show up at these meetings and try to facilitate the session and deal with the different interests, agendas, and perspectives in &#x201C;real time.&#x201D; Few advisors, however, are skilled enough, or fast enough on their feet, to deal with the many objections and concerns that surface during such meetings.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__39">But if you are diligent about finding out who is going to be at the meeting, and disciplined enough to call each of them, one at a time, in advance, you can then ask each person to share their take on the issues, their concerns, and their objectives. Prepared in this way, it will be easier to plan and to run the subsequent meeting(s) and to help bring the group to consensus. Even though the individual agendas will not always be reconciled, it is likely that significantly more progress in decision making and buy-in will be made. While the up-front investment may seem insignificant, the return on this investment is usually substantial.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__39">Most meetings also benefit from a quick summary of what was decided. People often leave the same meeting with different impressions of what was decided. Building trust also requires reducing ambiguities.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__39">It is tempting (and probably true) to think that conflicting agendas, priorities, and goals are the clients&#x2019; fault, not yours. However, unless you can develop the approaches and skills necessary to deal with these, your advice will not be acted upon, and you will not be seen as a helpful, useful advisor.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__39">Customizing Your Approach</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__39">Giving advice is an art, not a science. Jeswald Salacuse (in </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__39">The Art of Advice</Run>
          <Run Tag="__39">) rightly calls it a &#x201C;performing art.&#x201D; Most of us have to learn these skills by trial and error as our career progresses. Individual tips and tactics are helpful, but to apply any of them unthinkingly across the board with all clients would be a huge mistake. The essence of advice giving is the ability to design a process and means of interacting that fits each unique client situation. We all have clients who have little tolerance for Socratic reasoning and who say, &#x201C;Cut the nonsense; just tell me what you think.&#x201D; If that&#x2019;s what works with that client, then that&#x2019;s what we&#x2019;ll do. (We discuss different client types in Chapter 16.)</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__39">The burden, however, is still on the advisor to quickly understand each individual client&#x2019;s preferred style of interaction, and to be sufficiently flexible to deal with him or her in the manner that the client finds most comfortable and effective. The one thing the advisor must not do is commit to a single consultative style and say, &#x201C;Well, that&#x2019;s my style. The clients can take it or leave it.&#x201D; That really would be pompous, patronizing, and arrogant!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
