<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch20.html#ch20">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__140">20</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__140">Re-earning Trust Away from the Current Assignment</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__140">T</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__140">RUST AND RELATIONSHIPS</Run>
          <Run Tag="__140"> are built not only by activities connected to the current assignment. There are many opportunities to build your relationship with your client outside the demands of the current work.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__140">In order to help professional firms design and implement programs for relationship management, David has interviewed clients of firms representing a wide variety of professions and countries, to obtain their view of their relationships with their outside providers.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__140">Many of these clients&#x2019; concerns are similar. A few of the more commonly expressed client concerns are:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Disc" Margin="64,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14" Tag="__140">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__140">They are only interested in selling their services, not solving our problems.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__140">They don&#x2019;t do anything to make us feel our business is important to them. We are taken completely for granted. They never call up to inquire how our business is doing. We only see them when they want to sell something.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__140">There are few signs that they&#x2019;re really listening to us. They bring us generic issues faced by all companies. We want to hear about the specific opportunities for, and challenges facing, our company.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__140">We don&#x2019;t want to be &#x201C;romanced.&#x201D; We already have many opportunities to go to fancy dinners or attend sporting events. They should focus on being useful to us, not on becoming our friends.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__140">A number of key conclusions can be drawn from this list. It is clear that clients want their providers to </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__140">continually earn</Run>
          <Run Tag="__140"> their future business. Relationships cannot be taken for granted. It is equally clear that they don&#x2019;t want a &#x201C;sales pitch.&#x201D; Instead, the emphasis must be placed on investing the advisor&#x2019;s own (non-reimbursed) time to build the relationship. This is not always done. Rather than a relationship plan, many advisors draw up sales plans. The difference is readily apparent to clients.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__140">What Clients Want</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__140">What </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__140">do</Run>
          <Run Tag="__140"> clients want advisors to do to grow their relationship? Here are a few of the most commonly expressed client suggestions:</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Decimal" Margin="48,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__141">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Make an impact on our business, don&#x2019;t just be visible.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Do more things &#x201C;on spec&#x201D; (i.e., invest your time on preliminary work in new areas).</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Spend more time helping us think, and helping us develop strategies.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Lead our thinking. Tell us what our business is going to look like five or ten years from now.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__141">Jump</Run>
            <Run Tag="__141"> on any new pieces of information we have, so you can stay up-to-date on what&#x2019;s going on in our business. Use our data to give us an extra level of analysis. Ask for it, don&#x2019;t wait for us to give it to you.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Schedule some offsite meetings together. Join us for brainstorming sessions about our business.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Make an extra effort to understand how our business works: sit in on our meetings.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Help us see how we compare to others, both within and outside our industry.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Tell me why our competitors are doing what they&#x2019;re doing.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__141">Discuss with us other things we should be doing; we welcome any and all ideas!</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__141">What many of these suggestions have in common is that they are about expending serious effort on getting to know the client&#x2019;s business and industry in great depth, and being proactive in offering suggestions for improvement. Some of this can take place in the professional firm&#x2019;s &#x201C;back room&#x201D; (conducting studies, benchmarking, etc.). However, much will require greater (nonpaid) contact with the client. It is notable that while clients want more contact, they want it to be in settings that allow mutual discussions and explorations of the issues.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__141">It is also clear that clients want a business partner, not a false friend. The good news is that clients clearly do want us to bring them new ideas, and that they </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__141">want</Run>
          <Run Tag="__141"> a relationship.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__141">Stay in Touch</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__141">Clients&#x2019; comments clearly indicate that they want us to stay in touch. This is contrary to the instincts of many advisors (like our friend Rebecca in Chapter 15), who feel as though they are imposing on the client if they call when there is not a &#x201C;live&#x201D; project.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__141">The truth is there&#x2019;s nothing more destructive to trust than to call only when we want something. Great trusted advisors stay in regular contact with their clients, even if they are not currently working on a project for that client.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__141">To maintain trust when the project is over, we must recognize that it&#x2019;s never over, as long as we check in. The impact of our work continues long after we are gone, and in ways we often can&#x2019;t imagine. It is never too late to reestablish a relationship, even if significant time has elapsed. It may be harder as time goes by, but it is never too late!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__141">Creating Institutional Relationships</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">Among large firms with large clients, there is often a desire to try to build institutional relationships. As we have noted, trust is personal, not institutional, but that does not mean that this goal is impossible. If a professional firm wishes to develop an institutional relationship with a major client, it requires more than a single member of the firm (the relationship manager) focusing his or her attention on a few key decision makers.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__142">A proper relationship with a major &#x201C;account&#x201D; (a word that we dislike, for what we hope are obvious reasons) requires the full participation of a large number of people who service or deal with the client. Everyone who participates in serving the client can, and does, affect the relationship. Multiple contacts must be established, and a </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">consistency</Run>
          <Run Tag="__142"> of service and attentiveness must be attained. It&#x2019;s no good if each provider behaves in different ways, since a firm-wide reputation is built only if each person can be trusted and relied upon to operate to the same standards.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__142">Clearly, clients </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">want</Run>
          <Run Tag="__142"> their outside providers to recognize their specific needs and opportunities, and to customize any suggestions for additional work. This also requires teamwork among all of the outside firm&#x2019;s people, since the key relationship manager is often poorly positioned to identify the client&#x2019;s emerging issues.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">It is often the case that the client CEO and other headquarters personnel are among the last ones to know about emerging issues. Frequently, it is the client&#x2019;s junior executives and &#x201C;field&#x201D; people who are most aware of developing issues, and most willing to talk openly about them. Accordingly, junior professionals on the provider&#x2019;s team, who have the greatest contact with these people during the current engagement, are often best positioned to surface new needs.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">Many firms have developed such systems of relationship managers who are responsible for the firm&#x2019;s total relationship with each key client. These individuals have the responsibility of managing (and growing) their firm&#x2019;s relationship with major clients, coordinating professionals across the various disciplines of the firm, and often across geographic boundaries.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">To make such a system work, the relationship manager must act as the client&#x2019;s representative to the firm (perhaps even the client&#x2019;s advocate), ensuring that all of the firm&#x2019;s resources are brought to bear on the client&#x2019;s problems. The logic of this should be clear: If we ensure that the client&#x2019;s needs are met, the firm will benefit.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__142">Relationship managers are most effective when they focus on the (long-term) issue of strengthening the </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">relationship</Run>
          <Run Tag="__142">. Where relationship managers see themselves primarily as salespeople, primarily focused on generating more fees from the client, they are less well accepted by the client and become less effective.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__142">Many relationship managers see their role as carrying the primary burden of building the trust relationship between themselves as individuals and various client executives. This is usually a mistake. The most important part of a relationship officer&#x2019;s job is to </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">manage</Run>
          <Run Tag="__142"> the relationship, not to try to build it alone. He or she must be active in creating opportunities for other members of the professional firm&#x2019;s team to meet with additional client executives and begin new trust relationships.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__142">This can be done by offering to put on free internal seminars for the client organization, where new members of the professional firm have the chance to demonstrate their expertise and to meet other client personnel in a low-stress (non-selling) environment. An alternate approach is to offer the services of a colleague to attend a client&#x2019;s internal meeting (for free) as a way of both investing in the relationship (and being seen to do so) and opening the door for new relationships to form by new people meeting each other.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__143">Part of the job of the relationship manager is to create and energize the team serving their mutual client. This means devoting significant time to being a terrific coach.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__143">The relationship manager&#x2019;s task is to make the team members </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__143">want</Run>
          <Run Tag="__143"> to participate actively in serving and nurturing the relationship (not the &#x201C;account&#x201D;). This can be done by providing what they often do not find in their regular work, such as challenge and meaning. In principle, work for key clients should be exciting and challenging, even more than serving other kinds of clients.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__143">However, meaning and challenge should not be taken for granted. Amid the hurly-burly of busy professional lives, it is easy to lose sight of the significance of what one is working on. Effective relationship managers work at helping their team members find the excitement, the challenge and the drama in this client&#x2019;s problems.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__143">Effective relationship managers also work hard to make the people on their team look good. They create opportunities for other team members to participate in high-visibility activities that help their careers. They are willing to suppress their own ego needs and to work hard to give the team members valuable client exposure so they can begin to build their own trust relationships. Great relationship managers work hard to create new contacts for the team members, and they get them involved in stretching, learning activities that are out of the norm of the team members&#x2019; daily lives.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__143">Since the best way to get someone to cooperate with you is to do them a favor first, great relationship managers work hard to serve their team </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__143">before</Run>
          <Run Tag="__143"> they need to call on them. They work on the principle that if they serve their team well, the team will serve the client.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__143">Outstanding relationship managers think about ways to make it easier for their team to serve the client. They give them tools, research, and industry and client information, all in an easily digested form. They arrange for someone to read, summarize, and circulate </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__143">every</Run>
          <Run Tag="__143"> trade magazine, industry association publication, and financial analyst report in their client&#x2019;s industry, so that all team members are up-to-date about what&#x2019;s going on in the client&#x2019;s world.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__143">The most important fact to note about relationship management off the current assignment is that it is an investment activity for everyone involved. Significant (non-reimbursed) budgets must be set aside, and the relationship management program launched with a longer-term perspective than the traditional professional firm &#x201C;fee credits&#x201D; or &#x201C;bookings&#x201D; systems usually allow.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__143">The best news is that relationship management is in everyone&#x2019;s interests. Clients want it, and it benefits the firm by growing relationships and generating new fees. Done properly, it can also provide career-enhancing opportunities for every professional involved. Studies in many industries have proven that there is a clear link between profitability and success in nurturing relationships. It&#x2019;s hard work, but it&#x2019;s a clear path to economic success.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
