<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch12.html#ch12">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__91">12</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__91">Framing the Issue</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__91">F</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__91">RAMING</Run>
          <Run Tag="__91">, </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__91">THE THIRD STAGE</Run>
          <Run Tag="__91"> in trust creation, is the act of crystallizing and encapsulating the client&#x2019;s complex issues (and emotions) into a problem definition that, in an objective manner, provides both insight and a fresh way of thinking about the problem. In many advisory situations, an accurate problem statement is more than halfway to the solution.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__91">Of the five steps, framing is usually the most challenging, often the most rewarding, and almost always the most difficult. This is because framing is an inextricable combination of the rational and the emotional, and must sometimes be conceived and articulated in the middle of a conversation.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__91">Framing involves identifying (and enunciating) the essence of the issues at hand, usually something that is hidden, critical, fundamental, or all three. Identifying (and surfacing) the core &#x201C;gut&#x201D; issue in a client situation will usually involve an emotional aspect, in addition to the purely rational component.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__91">Rational Framing</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__91">There are two kinds of framing: rational framing and emotional framing. Generally, rational framing is far easier for advisors since it is in our comfort zone. It is what we are trained to do.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__91">Strategy consultants are especially prone to believing that their clients are buying their brilliance and insight. Most firms stress their ability to bring to the client the incisive application of intellect in such a way as to create new perspectives, and hence open up new routes to shareholder value.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__91">Lawyers, too, are expert at framing issues rationally. Such and such is an issue of tort law or constitutional law; it has this or that jurisdiction. Consider &#x201C;the issue is, what did the President know, and when did he know it?&#x201D; as a particularly successful example of legal, rational framing.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__91">Rational framing is a key skill in the package of skills that advisors traditionally bring to bear. It is done in such deceptively simple ways as generating a list, drawing a diagram, or sketching out a process or approach. At root, all rational framing consists of distilling a complex set of issues down to a few critical variables.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__91">Consider the use of a formal model (like our five-stage trust model), a method particularly beloved (and arguably overused) by management consultants. The reason for the prevalence of use of this technique is that the human mind has limitations on the amount of information it can process.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__91">Amazing though humans are, we are considerably limited in the number of perspectives we can consider simultaneously. When we are confronted by too much complexity, we often fall into an endless cycle of frustration until we, or someone else, manages to simplify the problem statement. Then progress toward a solution can begin. Formal models do just that.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__92">Rational framing looks so much like the &#x201C;essence&#x201D; of many professions that it&#x2019;s easy to forget it is only a </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__92">middle</Run>
          <Run Tag="__92"> step in a process of trust creation. The most brilliant, incisive insight will fall on completely deaf ears if the advisor has not yet earned the right to frame the issue by going through the necessary preceding steps of engaging and listening.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__92">Advisors sometimes stress too much the need to create (and protect) proprietary framing methodologies or models. We think this concern is misplaced. There are relatively few great truths in life. The effectiveness of the advisor does not lie so much in the invention of the next (proprietary) paradigm as it does in finding the way to lead a particular client, with a particular problem, into seeing the </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__92">relevance</Run>
          <Run Tag="__92"> of an old (or new) paradigm.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__92">Emotional Framing</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__92">Rational framing is a critical, even necessary, component of effective advising; but it is hardly sufficient. Frequently, advisory relationships (or discussions) get stuck in an emotional backwater. Ideas, conversation, and relationships stop flowing freely; they stagnate and begin to hamper effectiveness. Something must break the logjam that is inhibiting the discussion.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__92">In such situations, the problem is not caused by (and cannot be solved by) a rational insight. What&#x2019;s causing the problem is predominantly an emotional or political issue.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__92">David was once working with the executive committee of a professional firm on the topic of introducing new standards of performance and new accountabilities for all of the firm&#x2019;s partners. At one point in the meeting, they were discussing the (obvious?) managerial issue that something cannot be a standard if it is not enforced, or if the firm tolerates noncompliance.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__92">On the surface, all seemed to be going well, and everyone seemed to be in agreement. However, David noticed some people shifting uncomfortably in their seats and a number of whispered side conversations going on around the table. &#x201C;Something is going on here,&#x201D; he thought, but he was not entirely sure what.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__92">He decided to try to address the issue. Calling on one of the whisperers, the following conversation ensued:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__92">D</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__92">AVID</Run>
          <Run Tag="__92">: Fred, I&#x2019;m concerned that we are not getting all of the issues out on the table. Is there a complexity about doing this program at this firm that I&#x2019;m not aware of?</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__92">F</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__92">RED</Run>
          <Run Tag="__92">: Well, you seem to be saying that if one of our most powerful partners doesn&#x2019;t do this new thing, then someone will have to tackle him until he gets into compliance.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__92">D</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__92">AVID</Run>
          <Run Tag="__92">: That&#x2019;s exactly what we are all saying, I think. If exceptions are made to this standard for &#x201C;big hitters,&#x201D; then it won&#x2019;t be credible as a firmwide standard to everyone else. Does anyone disagree with that?</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__93">The room fell silent. Finally, Fred spoke again.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__93">F</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__93">RED</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93">: But who&#x2019;s going to go and talk to this guy? I can&#x2019;t imagine telling our biggest rainmaker that he&#x2019;s got to change!</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__93">D</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__93">AVID</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93">: I have an opinion, but before I give it, do you want to say who </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__93">you</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93"> think should have the responsibility?</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__93">F</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__93">RED</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93">: I suppose it should be the managing partner.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__93">At this point, Tom, the managing partner (who had been relatively silent,) jumped in.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__93">T</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__93">OM</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93">: Oh, I&#x2019;ll do it, but I need to know that the rest of the executive committee is solidly behind me. I can&#x2019;t do it, and won&#x2019;t do it if one or more of you break ranks. Do I have your full support? Will you all back me up if we go forward with this?</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__93">F</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__93">RED</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93">: We&#x2019;ll back you up, Tom. But to be candid, you&#x2019;ve never done such a thing before.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="-16" Margin="0,0,16,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__93">D</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__93">AVID</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93">: Can I jump back in? None of you have done this before, and that&#x2019;s the point. We&#x2019;re here to discuss whether you </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__93">want</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93"> to do things differently from now on. You don&#x2019;t have to go through with this if you don&#x2019;t want to. But, as Fred has helped us understand, this is as much about having the courage and determination to see this through as it is about whether or not the plan is a good one. Shall we explore what it will really require from each of you?</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__93">It should be obvious from this dialogue that a hornet&#x2019;s nest of emotional and political issues had been raised. But what progress would this firm have made if they had not been raised?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__93">Earlier in his career, David would not have had the courage to raise this topic openly. It would have been suppressed, and burst out only in stolen hallway conversations during coffee breaks.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__93">However, we have all learned that solving clients&#x2019; problems, in every profession, means helping the client (or the client&#x2019;s organization) solve not only the technical aspects of the problem but also the very real emotions that surround any kind of significant decision making.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__93">Emotional framing is first and foremost about the courage to take a personal risk and surface hidden emotions. Naturally, this is not easy. But it can become an easier process than you think if you can remember that this is usually about framing the client&#x2019;s emotions (and not ours!). They&#x2019;re thinking about their situations and their reactions to them. So spending time focusing on how they make </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__93">us</Run>
          <Run Tag="__93"> feel is not really the issue. It makes things so much easier if you just have to deal with their emotions and not your own at the same time.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">One of our friends, Joe, tells the story of a &#x201C;lost sale&#x201D; years ago. His client (a CEO) needed to do a major restructuring of his organization. The restructuring would involve asset sales, redeployments, and the laying-off of three to five thousand employees. Joe was not only the leading candidate to win the work, but at least for the moment, no competitors were being considered.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__94">Discussions proceeded well. Toward the end of the second meeting with the client, everything seemed to be progressing as it should, and the meeting was heading toward a final handshake to close the deal. Then in an abrupt change of mood, the CEO leaned back in his chair and, shaking his head sadly, said, &#x201C;Joe, what are we gonna do about all those people?&#x201D; Joe was taken aback, and in the next instant, he made the </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">wrong</Run>
          <Run Tag="__94"> decision. He reverted to the upbeat mood of a moment before, slapped the CEO on the arm and said, &#x201C;Hey, no problem, Bill. We&#x2019;ll line &#x2019;em all up with outplacement counselors, set &#x2019;em up in a separate building, they&#x2019;ll be out of here in no time. No problem.&#x201D;</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">But in the back of his mind he knew it wasn&#x2019;t right to make a joke of (and thereby cover up) the client&#x2019;s emotions. The meeting ended inconclusively. The next meeting got postponed, then never happened. In fact, the entire restructuring didn&#x2019;t happen for several more years, and, when it did (as Joe tells it), the layoffs totaled two to three times what they would have been originally.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">In his mind, rightly or wrongly, Joe holds himself at least partly accountable for the incremental job losses, because he didn&#x2019;t have, in that moment, the ability to deal with the profound and personal sadness that the CEO was feeling. He thought that if he had had the courage and skill to help the CEO wrestle with the emotional complexity of the decision when it first arose, the pain and suffering felt by a lot of people (the client included) could have been avoided.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__94">Naming and Claiming</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">A useful technique for emotional framing is a technique that we call naming and claiming. This phrase refers to the breakthrough that can come from speaking what hitherto may have been &#x201C;unsayable,&#x201D; articulating something that was previously too uncomfortable to be stated.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">Naming and claiming is characterized by three factors:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Decimal" Margin="48,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__94">An acknowledgment of the difficulty of raising the issue</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__94">An acceptance of the responsibility for raising it</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__94">A direct statement of the issue itself</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">Many cultures have a phrase for such situations, where the embarrassment from the passage of time exceeds the original situation itself. We call it &#x201C;the elephant in the parlor.&#x201D; This is a phrase for the &#x201C;things that cannot be said,&#x201D; even though everyone knows them to be true. These situations can only be handled by emotional framing.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__94">Using emotional framing is the equivalent of dynamiting a stream that has become clogged up to the point of dysfunctionality. There are echoes of emotional framing in psychotherapy and religion, in the bringing forth (through counseling or confession) of things that were previously left unsaid.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__95">Ellen&#x2019;s Story</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">Ellen is a partner in an accounting firm who attended one of our programs. She was faced one day with the need to present some difficult news to her client, the controller.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">As she began to deliver the bad news, she noticed that &#x201C;the client&#x2019;s face was getting red, and his knuckles were getting white.&#x201D; We can all imagine the thousand and one emotions and thoughts that could be instantly conjured up by the active mind sitting in Ellen&#x2019;s chair in that moment: &#x201C;How can I get out of here? There goes the account,&#x201D; and the like.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">Yet Ellen took a different approach. She paused, took a deep breath, and said, &#x201C;You look a little angry.&#x201D; And then she waited, silently, for the client to respond.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">After a moment, the client shouted, &#x201C;No, I&#x2019;m not angry! Not at all!&#x201D; He then added, &#x201C;Well, I mean, not at you; I&#x2019;m angry at our people. I mean, you shouldn&#x2019;t have to be the one to bring this news to me, it&#x2019;s embarrassing. I mean, I&#x2019;m glad you&#x2019;ve pointed it out. Yes, I&#x2019;m angry, though not at you.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">Ellen&#x2019;s reward for asking that question was clear and instant. She found out what the truth was, thereby freeing herself from the fears she had created internally. She allowed the client to blow off steam, to say just what it was that concerned him. She allowed the client to articulate the problem at hand, thus moving the conversation productively in the direction of a joint solution. And she created a further bond between herself and the client by being willing to reach outside her own fears and be of instant, personal service to the other person, her client.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">The point here is not that Ellen had been in the right. The point is that Ellen chose consciously to focus not on her own mind (the thousand emotions and thoughts, each demanding its own version of talking faster and slicker) but on the mind of her client. She made a simple observation, one clearly about her client, not herself.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">Had Ellen gone with her own fears, she probably would have delivered the bad news as quickly as possible and run for cover. If she had not asked the question, she would have left believing (incorrectly) that the client&#x2019;s anger was directed at her. Even if that had been the case, she would never have known if she had not asked the question (or made the observation).</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">Emotional framing is about taking risk. It requires some courage to say something that people are generally afraid to say. Ellen had the courage to treat the emotional signals (clenched fists, red face) that her client was sending as objective facts, rather than as judgments about her.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__95">Framing and Blaming</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">Most initial attempts at framing, perhaps especially those made by clients, are laden with blame. &#x201C;I can&#x2019;t get the marketing people to listen to me.&#x201D; &#x201C;We need better training.&#x201D; &#x201C;It won&#x2019;t work if the CEO isn&#x2019;t behind it.&#x201D; All these are typical problem statements that are not, from a trusted advisor&#x2019;s viewpoint, sufficiently free of blame to constitute useful framing statements.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__95">Blame truly gets in the way of effectively framing the issue. In fact, it gets in the way of effective advising in general. An advisor spending any energy blaming a client (or almost anyone else) is wasting energy that could be focused on doing something useful for the client. Even in the rare cases where blame is &#x201C;justified,&#x201D; it is useless at best. Blame is a defense mechanism protecting the ego of the one doing the blaming. As such, it is just another form of self-orientation.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__96">By systematically telling the truth and eliminating blame from his or her repertoire, a trusted advisor can maneuver toward full ownership of a blame-free problem statement that can be acted upon, evaluated, and transcended.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__96">How to Implement Emotional Framing</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__96">When we discuss examples such as those given above, we find that people can &#x201C;get&#x201D; every example we mention, but when describing their own &#x201C;elephant&#x201D; situations, they feel that &#x201C;My situation is different. There&#x2019;s a lot at stake here; it&#x2019;s not play.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__96">No, it&#x2019;s not play. That&#x2019;s why we all have to accept it as central to our roles as advisors. The essence of it is moving from a defensive or blaming attitude to an attitude of taking responsibility.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__96">Being willing to move from blame to responsibility feels risky. Why should I give up the security of being able to blame someone else for difficult situations? Ironically, naming and claiming is a technique for accepting responsibility that actually reduces personal risk.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__96">It&#x2019;s a technique that makes judicious use of caveats. The caveats are about how difficult it is to raise the issue in question and to take personal responsibility for the consequences of it being raised. Feel more risk? Add more caveats. Add as many as it takes, stringing them together up to the point at which you have just slightly overcompensated for the perceived risk of the issue you&#x2019;re about to frame. Choose from the following list of responsibility-taking caveats:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Decimal" Margin="48,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__96">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">It&#x2019;s probably just me, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I must have been tuned out for a moment, I&#x2019;m sorry, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I&#x2019;m sure you covered this before, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I&#x2019;m sorry to interrupt, but I just can&#x2019;t get this out of my head about . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">You&#x2019;ve probably thought of this already, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I wish I knew, but I just don&#x2019;t know how to handle this concern . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I realize you have a strong preference for XYZ, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I&#x2019;m probably thinking about this all wrong, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I&#x2019;m not sure if this is on point, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I may not have understood this right, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I don&#x2019;t know exactly how to say this, so I hope you&#x2019;ll help me, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I&#x2019;m not sure if I&#x2019;m being inappropriate in bringing this up, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__96">I hope you&#x2019;ll forgive me for not knowing quite how to say this, but . . .</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__96">(Note that these are all phrases used by the TV character Lieutenant Columbo! See Chapter 17.)</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__96">Having posed enough responsibility-taking caveats, say the thing that must be said. Although emotional framing appears to be very risky, it offers enormous payoffs. Furthermore, it is the process of managing those risks by raising hidden topics, (emotional framing) that unleashes the payoffs. We cannot stress its importance enough.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
