<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch7.html#ch7">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__55">7</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__55">Sincerity or Technique?</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__55">I</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__55">N PRECEDING CHAPTERS</Run>
          <Run Tag="__55"> we have offered advice on actions and words that serve to build trust (and relationships). However, we often get questions and comments from participants in our programs about the issue of sincerity. Is building trust about the use of the correct tactics, or do you have to like your clients, be interested in them or care about them, to make the tactics effective?</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">Even more challenging is the question: Is it appropriate to use techniques if you don&#x2019;t truly care? Is it possible to &#x201C;manipulate&#x201D; the emotions of another person without being manipulative? We think so.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">An example may illustrate the point.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__55">A friend of ours, Jim, is a self-made man, having bought and turned around a company single-handedly. He &#x201C;gives back&#x201D; in many ways, one being the teaching of a course at a local business school. At the first meeting of each semester, he brings a Polaroid camera and a white sheet for background, and he photographs each person. Then he tells them that he will memorize their faces, their names, their undergraduate schools, </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">and</Run>
          <Run Tag="__55"> their companies by the next class.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">He then works very hard for the next week to deliver on his promise to a class of forty-five students. And, he stresses, he is not a natural at names and faces. He runs through the pictures and data, using flash cards to memorize the information.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">For the next class, everyone shows up to see if he can do it. He does. He dazzles. And everyone stays throughout the semester. His no-show and dropout rates are zero.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">Is what Jim does premeditated? Absolutely. Is it sincere or is it manipulative? We would argue that those are needlessly loaded words. Yes, he is consciously using a technique, visible even to his &#x201C;clients.&#x201D; Yet it is equally clear that he is sincere, that he cares. Why else would a busy person teach a course for a small amount of money that he doesn&#x2019;t need, and devote hours of his valuable personal time to memorizing people&#x2019;s names?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">Our advice is simple. If you already care about a client, then practice the behaviors that exhibit caring. If, on the other hand, you&#x2019;re only going through the motions, then you will be found out and will fail.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">So, does that mean that if you do not actually care for the client, you should not adopt the tactics, techniques, and advice we recommend? No, that&#x2019;s not our advice, either. Remember Rodgers and Hammerstein&#x2019;s song &#x201C;Whistle a Happy Tune?&#x201D; It points out that &#x201C;when I fool the people, I find, I fool myself as well!&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__55">There is an old debate about whether you get people to change their actions by changing their attitudes, or change their attitudes by getting them to first change their actions. Naturally, it </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__55">can</Run>
          <Run Tag="__55"> work both ways. But it is often easier to first change one&#x2019;s actions (adopt caring behaviors) as a way to achieve caring than it is to change one&#x2019;s mental state (which takes more time).</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">Sincerity, the way we usually mean it, has to do with intentions; we assume it comes from within. But our clients have no way to observe sincerity except through external behaviors. From certain behaviors (attention paid, interest shown, advance work done, empathetic listening), we infer the internal state we call sincerity.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">Thus, to ask whether we must care first or try out the actions first amounts to asking whether we should start from within, or without. The only right answer is yes to both.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">By starting with caring (working from the inside out), we open ourselves to possibilities and become willing to go where the client will take us. The skill or action behaviors can then fall on fertile ground.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">By starting with new external behaviors or skills, we open ourselves to new information and stimuli that encourage our thinking and allow for a fresh focus on the client. We do this when we generate shared enthusiasm for questions, eagerly exploring together the next implication.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">Sometimes it&#x2019;s true that &#x201C;you can act your way into right thinking better than you can think your way into right acting,&#x201D; or &#x201C;you fake it till you make it.&#x201D; And sometimes the reverse is true. We are generally better off working from both ends to the middle.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__56">Sincerity </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">is</Run>
          <Run Tag="__56"> crucial to both trust and relationships. If you have it and can show it, you&#x2019;ll do well. If you try to &#x201C;fake it&#x201D; (i.e., use the tactics without really caring), but </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">always</Run>
          <Run Tag="__56"> act that way, you&#x2019;ll probably end up creating something that is indistinguishable from the genuine article, either to the client or to yourself.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__56">What will not work is the use of </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">occasional</Run>
          <Run Tag="__56"> tactics that are inconsistent with the way you </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">normally</Run>
          <Run Tag="__56"> behave. These will soon be spotted for what they are: phony, insincere, and clumsy efforts, and they will not only be ineffective but will also create an adverse reaction. There&#x2019;s no point to faking it, unless you plan to keep it up for the rest of your relationship. And if you always </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">do</Run>
          <Run Tag="__56"> keep it up, always exhibiting sincere caring behaviors, the distinction will become academic. As Gerald Weinberg said in his book </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">The Secrets of Consulting</Run>
          <Run Tag="__56">, &#x201C;The trick of earning trust is to avoid all tricks.&#x201D;</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__56">What If You Don&#x2019;t Care for Them?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">We are not so idealistic as to believe that we can all care for everybody we encounter. Sometimes, even after trying very hard and applying every idea in this book (and more besides), you may find that you just can&#x2019;t empathize with this client. What do you do then?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">Consider the options:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Decimal" Margin="48,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__56">Keep serving the client, but don&#x2019;t make the effort to build the relationship</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__56">Keep serving the client, but apply the trust techniques without sincerity</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__56">Pass the client on to a colleague</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__56">Resign the account.</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">Not an attractive set of options, is it?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__56">In Option 1 (serve the client, but don&#x2019;t try to get close), you will not only miss all the benefits of being trusted, but you will have a less than fulfilling work life. Our slogan is: &#x201C;Life is too short to work with idiots; and that&#x2019;s just as true when it&#x2019;s our clients&#x2019; lives and we&#x2019;re the idiots!&#x201D; A lack of chemistry between you and the client may be as much (if not more) your fault as it is the client&#x2019;s.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">Regardless of blame, if there is no chemistry there, then it only makes sense to either create the chemistry (somehow!) or move on. Our view is that Option 1 makes everyone a loser, advisor and client, and should be dropped from consideration.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__57">Option 2, keep serving and try to fake it, is clearly worth trying for a while, as we have argued above. If you try hard to find the connections and empathy between you and a client, you often can. But not always! So, should you keep faking it? Not in our view. We can imagine nothing worse than to spend our whole lives faking it. If you&#x2019;ve </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">really</Run>
          <Run Tag="__57"> tried to build a relationship and it&#x2019;s not working, move on to Option 3.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">Option 3 is attractive when it is possible: Few clients are completely unlovable, and personal chemistry is exactly that. Someone you cannot connect with may be a dream client for a colleague. Consider this seriously.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__57">Option 4 (resign) is the ultimate step, but there are occasions when it must be taken. If you can&#x2019;t bring yourself to act as a caring, trusted advisor, you </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">will</Run>
          <Run Tag="__57"> be less effective, perhaps even ineffective. You may think that financial pressures force to keep serving such clients, but this is a very short-term view. You do yourself no good by continuing to serve clients who can see that you are not fully engaged. The damage to your reputation will outlast any cash penalty you pay while searching for a client you can enthusiastically serve. Reputation before revenue!</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">That&#x2019;s all very well and good, you may be thinking, if you happen to be a sole practitioner or the senior person on the engagement. But what if you&#x2019;re a junior professional or part of a large team? What if you don&#x2019;t feel you have the luxury of resigning the account, or even passing the client on to a colleague?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">We have three pieces of advice for someone in such a situation. First, check your motives. Are you sure you&#x2019;ve tried everything you know to find ways to relate to this client? Are you sure you&#x2019;re not looking for a reason to avoid some other aspect of unpleasantness in the assignment? Are you sure the client would or has expressed equal levels of concern?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">Second, put the issue in perspective. If it&#x2019;s not life-threatening, career-threatening or client-threatening, then how long must you live with the situation? If it&#x2019;s a matter of only a few months, it may not be worth the energy required to resolve it.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">Third, if the issue is real and material, we advise you to raise it directly with the senior engagement manager. That person has as much at stake as you do. If they convince you that you are wrong, you gain peace of mind. If you convince them you are right, they improve their odds of providing good client service.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">If you both remain unconvinced by what the other has to say, then you may have also learned something about your ability to connect with yet another person in your work life. This does happen, once in a while. At the same time, remember the sage person&#x2019;s advice: &#x201C;I was amazed at how many fools I ran into until I noticed the common denominator in all those interactions: me.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__57">Why do we in the professions so often avoid this whole topic? In David&#x2019;s book </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">True Professionalism</Run>
          <Run Tag="__57">, he reported that a common survey result is that the typical professional really likes his or her clients only about 20 percent to 30 percent of the time! The rest are mostly &#x201C;tolerated.&#x201D;</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__57">The professions include many people who are hugely talented intellectually, but some have paid less attention in their lives to social skills, and even less to emotional skills. Such people have a very difficult time accepting things that look, to them, like failure. The thought of a client saying, &#x201C;This isn&#x2019;t working&#x201D; is essentially indistinguishable to them from a client saying, &#x201C;I dislike you and look down upon you as a person.&#x201D; What to others might appear a simple social fact is experienced as a highly personal criticism.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">The truth is there are very few people who have the capacity to relate to everyone. It follows that there are going to be cases where &#x201C;the glue doesn&#x2019;t stick.&#x201D; Ask yourself what percentage of people you have met in the business world really grab you, excite you, or make you want to work with them? Then ask what percentage of people in the business world make you want to resign your career, rather than have to spend any more time with them? And the (presumably large) middle category of people probably determines how excited you are about your profession overall.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__58">Assuming you&#x2019;re like the rest of us, then at a minimum the same </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">percentage</Run>
          <Run Tag="__58"> of people whom you dislike will dislike you. And, from the broad middle category, there will be varying degrees of indifference about the prospect of working with you.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">Worse yet, the people you dislike are not necessarily the same ones who dislike you. Just because you like someone does not mean they return the feeling. Even if the percentage of &#x201C;non-likes&#x201D; is the same between professionals and clients, the total number of fits will be less. No wonder we have cases of non-fit! Some nontrivial percentage of potential relationships just will not work.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">A good rule to remember is that, in relationships, there are no win-lose or lose-win combinations: There are only win-wins and lose-loses. If the fit is not there for one party, then, just as for couples who ultimately divorce, it will, in the end, not work for either of them. To speak the truth about the disparity may be difficult, but it is usually the most efficient way out, not to mention the kindest.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__58">Client or Friend?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">Does all of this mean you have to make every client your friend? Not at all. You can be interested in someone without being their friend. You can deal with them as individual human beings, and avoid treating them as people in a role, without pretending that they are your bosom buddy. Clients quickly see through these false friendships, often built on extended conversations about golf, football, and similar topics.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__58">Many professionals worry that it may be &#x201C;unprofessional&#x201D; to get that close to a client. We don&#x2019;t agree. Showing interest in the person does not mean intruding into private areas. We think it is unprofessional </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">not</Run>
          <Run Tag="__58"> to show an interest in your client. To convince someone that they should view you as their trusted advisor, you must first convince them that you are committed to them. McDonald&#x2019;s likes to describe professionals that serve them (such as advertising agencies) as having &#x201C;ketchup in their veins.&#x201D;</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">Does this mean that you actually have to care? Yes, you do actually have to care, if you want to be a trusted advisor. If you want to be merely a vendor, you don&#x2019;t.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">Rob developed a great relationship with Arnold, a director of a major firm. This hadn&#x2019;t been easy, as Arnold was pretty demanding, intellectually and otherwise. When Arnold left the company, Rob found that it was much more difficult to be as committed to the company relationship as he once was.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__58">Rob tried really hard, certainly liked the people who replaced Arnold, and continued to do good work with and for them. He was given more work to do, but his heart really wasn&#x2019;t in it in the same way. He thought he behaved as he always had, but the strength of the relationship gradually diminished. Without true feeling, tactics will lose their power. Even when applied by someone who teaches this stuff!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__59">Should you socialize with your clients? Occasional socializing can be enjoyable, but earning trust is not about golf games, dinners, and opera performances. While socializing is not necessary, being sociable is. It&#x2019;s the window into the clients&#x2019; selves as people, their needs, hopes, and fears.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__59">It&#x2019;s the Journey, Not the Destination</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__59">Most of us have very keen instincts about what our romantic partners are looking for in us. If they are driven by a genuine liking for us, we see it exhibited in a thousand ways, from being willing to pursue common interests to looking us in the eye.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__59">On the other hand, if our romantic interest&#x2019;s objectives are aimed solely at something else (prestige, sex, money, comfort) we react negatively, and strongly so. The tension generated in relationships by unaligned interests is huge.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__59">So it is in business. When we are buying something, we have very little difficulty in detecting whether or not someone has our interests at heart. Most people are too caught up in their own concerns to genuinely exhibit care for another&#x2019;s needs.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__59">However, on those rare occasions when salespeople actually transcend their own concerns and are attentive to customer needs, the effectiveness of the sales process is dramatically enhanced.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__59">One of the most important lessons to learn is that to earn trust, you must bet on the long-term benefit of the relationship. No relationship is without its rough spots; all relationships are cyclical. The hallmark of trusted advisors is that they don&#x2019;t bail out when times get tough.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__59">We don&#x2019;t want people to be interested in us as a means to an end, as a destination for their own purposes. We want people to be interested in us as fellow-voyagers, people who care about us enough to go on a journey with us.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
