<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch18.html#ch18">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__131">18</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__131">The Role of Trust in Getting Hired</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__131">D</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__131">ALTON WAS A</Run>
          <Run Tag="__131"> (disguised) management-consulting firm with an excellent process for new client selling. It pioneered the application of industrial sales techniques to professional services. It disproved conclusively the idea rampant in the professions that the person who sells the work is the only person the client wants to do the work.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__131">Dalton had a four-step sales and service process, with entirely different people and organizational units at each step in the process. It worked staggeringly well for a number of years, but the successful sales model turned out to hold the seeds of its own destruction.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__131">Part of Dalton&#x2019;s genius was to create specialists in lead generation, specialists in closing, specialists in diagnostics, and specialists in delivery. All were distinct parts of the organization, with distinct measurement and reward systems. And all were very professional and competent in a new client situation.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__131">The delivery organization viewed its job, not surprisingly, as delivering results that were at least as good as, and preferably better than, the client&#x2019;s expectations in terms of budget, deliverables, timing, and benefits from both revenue enhancement and cost savings. They did </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__131">not</Run>
          <Run Tag="__131"> perceive selling to be part of their job, since that was the task of the other three divisions of the organization.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__131">The lead generation group, not surprisingly, viewed their task as one of identifying and qualifying new clients. They didn&#x2019;t see it as their job to call on existing clients; and in fact the other three parts of the organization would probably have resented it if they had. Ditto for the &#x201C;closers&#x201D; and the diagnosticians. Their job was to process the leads from the step before them.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__131">The delivery team saw its job as executing a defined specification and budget. They thought of themselves as professionals, and took pride in the work they did. But their definition of professionalism rarely included the idea that they should be on the lookout for other opportunities for improvement the client might have.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__131">The clients didn&#x2019;t usually think about expansion opportunities or follow-on work. When they did, they tended to focus on the delivery organization, with whom they were most acquainted and with whom they worked daily. But that group was not skilled at selling, and in fact viewed selling as a detriment to and distraction from meeting their primary goal: delivery on time and on budget.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__131">The result was a perpetually low client retention machine. Profitability and margins were rather low, but as long as a steady flow of new clients kept growth high, no one much minded. However, when demand for Dalton&#x2019;s primary service line declined somewhat, and when Dalton began to run out of prime category clients, the engine began to run out of steam, and Dalton&#x2019;s fortunes rapidly declined.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__131">While the case of Dalton Consulting might show that selling and service don&#x2019;t have to coexist in the same person, it reveals that there needs to be a mechanism to relate them. This case study is about much more than the failure of an existing-client sales program. It is about how the two capabilities are integrally related.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__132">The point is </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">not</Run>
          <Run Tag="__132"> that you can&#x2019;t have specialized organizations around the functions of sales and service. We think Dalton made some important innovations in this regard. What the case </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">does</Run>
          <Run Tag="__132"> say is that there must be </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">some</Run>
          <Run Tag="__132"> way to combine the professional perspective of always seeking different opportunities with that of seeking excellence in delivering that which has already been noticed. Having the two roles in one person or in one organizational unit are fairly obvious ways to achieve that combination.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__132">Integrating Sales and Service</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">While most professionals would not go so far as Dalton, they would nevertheless acknowledge a significant difference between selling one&#x2019;s services and providing the service. First we get the client to agree to the work (that&#x2019;s selling). Then we do the work (that&#x2019;s serving). What could be more clear?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">But the more you try to define the difference, the harder it gets to make the distinction. How does one sell? By demonstrating (not asserting) to a client that we have something to offer and that we are someone in whom they can place their trust. These are essentially serving actions.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">How does one serve? Serving means helping the client and meeting his or her needs in such a way that the client is delighted, wants to hire us again, and tells all their friends and business acquaintances about us. What is that if not selling?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">The truth is, sales and service, when thought of properly, converge. The two are flip sides of the same coin. And the name of that coin is acting like a trusted advisor and a caring professional.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__132">Service as Selling</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">Most advisors are a little uncomfortable with overt selling. They would like to believe that the quality of their work speaks for itself, that the need for their services is self-evident to the client and that it is therefore unnecessary to belabor the obvious in selling. Alas, this is not always true.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">However, if we think of the task not as selling (&#x201C;How do I push what we&#x2019;ve got&#x201D;), but as getting hired (&#x201C;How do I convince this person to put his or her trust in me?&#x201D;), then the required activities become a great deal clearer.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">Imagine the following scenario: You are invited, along with three competitors, to participate in a &#x201C;beauty contest,&#x201D; a competition among firms to gain a significant contract or piece of business. The client is not a service novice and is quite willing to give you (and your competitors) considerable pre-presentation access to several of their key people. End-runs, however, are frowned upon.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">The client makes it quite clear that a decision will be made from among several firms and that the decision will be based largely on what they hear at a final presentation. Up to three hours are allotted to each firm. How should you spend your three hours? You could, of course, do the standard presentation. Or you could dress it up with a number of techniques to enhance presentational effectiveness, many of which are very sound.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__132">There is another option, however. Get to work immediately! Use the allotted three hours as the first three hours of the scheduled project. The logic of this approach is simple. In professional services, where the &#x201C;good&#x201D; being bought is not only expensive but also intangible and often vague, the seller who succeeds is the seller who can show the buyer just what it feels like to be in a relationship together.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">This is because most buyers of professional services, even relatively experienced ones, are quite aware of a number of risks. There is financial risk, emotional risk, the risk of lost time, the risk of embarrassment in case of a wrong decision, career risk, and so on. An advisor who can reduce all those risks by demonstrating (with visceral impact) how it will feel to work together is at a significant advantage. This is also why the individual (or firm) with the relationship has such an advantage in professional services: &#x201C;The devil you know is better than the one you don&#x2019;t.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__133">Hence the best selling technique is to not sell, but to commence the service process. Many professionals, in their business development activities, will </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">talk about</Run>
          <Run Tag="__133"> serving, rather than actually serving. (&#x201C;It&#x2019;s going to be wonderful once you start paying, we promise you. But we won&#x2019;t show you anything until money changes hands.&#x201D;)</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">One of the worst forms of self-delusion is to assume that one is selling specialized knowledge and that there is a limited amount of it to go around. This preconception leads professionals to resist invitations to take a point of view, to refuse to go out on a limb. Through a combination of fear and of belief that you shouldn&#x2019;t &#x201C;give away&#x201D; the goods until the client has paid, the professional loses both new work and a relationship.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">The professions, in a sense, sell confidence, security, and ease. No client wants to buy air unless they can breathe it first. No client wants to buy a painting without seeing it. If given any choice at all, clients prefer to buy based on a sample.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__133">Selling as Service</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">Most of us would agree that, if we see something bad about to happen to our clients, we have a professional obligation to point out the situation to them. And it is not much of a stretch to say that we should therefore do the same if we see a significant opportunity for improvement.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">Do we also agree that all of our clients, at any point in time, are far from perfect, that they are all faced with a great number of opportunities for improvement across a number of dimensions? If that is the case, don&#x2019;t we have some professional obligation to continually keep an eye out for those opportunities to the best of our ability? Then why do we act on it so rarely?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">To be professional, we must point out possibilities. Some call that selling. We call it contributing ideas. Good selling requires giving the client a taste of what it feels like to work together. That feels like serving. Good sales is good service is good sales, and so on.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">There is very little difference between what we have just described as a professional obligation, and what someone else might call selling. After all, both involve noticing a legitimate opportunity for improvement, and raising the awareness of the client about the significance and benefits of taking the action suggested.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__133">Frequently, it seems that advisors don&#x2019;t just leave business on the table, they actually leave opportunities for clients unnoted. This means that, to some extent, they are behaving unprofessionally. In order to behave in a more professional manner, we must understand what gets in the way of pointing out client opportunities.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__134">The real link is between the ethos of selling and the ethos of serving. To act professionally, an advisor must at all times have the client&#x2019;s best interests at heart.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
