<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch17.html#ch17">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__129">17</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__129">The Lieutenant Columbo Approach</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__129">S</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__129">OMETIMES A METAPHOR MORE CONCISELY</Run>
          <Run Tag="__129"> captures and conveys meaning better than can be done by a collection of words. Such may be the case with the television character Lieutenant Columbo, who embodies a number of characteristics that can be useful for successful advisors.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__129">For the uninitiated, Lt. Columbo is a television character, played by Peter Falk successfully for three decades. Columbo is a detective in the Los Angeles Police Homicide Bureau. By all rights, this ought to make him an imposing character. Yet he is anything but.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__129">In the </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__129">Columbo</Run>
          <Run Tag="__129"> episodes, we are privy from the start to the insider&#x2019;s view of the crime. We know who the criminal is. Thus, unlike Perry Mason, we are not caught up in the game of playing detective. The game in which we are caught up is that of watching a master detective play the game of uncovering the truth.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__129">And how he plays it! From the start, Columbo has his (correct) suspicions. And inevitably, the criminal begins to let his (or her) guard down. The criminals begin convinced that they are invincible; as time goes on, it appears that luck conspires against them. Of course, it isn&#x2019;t luck at all. It is Columbo&#x2019;s death grasp.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__129">The key to Columbo lies in his style and, perhaps, even his character. It does not lie in his method. This is the first parallel to successful consulting. He disdains official police methodology, preferring to go for customized, on-off, situational gut-feel and instinct, in the belief that his behavior will lead the criminal to let down his guard.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__129">Columbo&#x2019;s style is informal, even sloppy, to a fault. He drives an old Peugeot, wears a rumpled trench coat, and continually smokes what look like very cheap cigars. His gestures are familiar ones of befuddlement, distraction, puzzlement, and inability to process information. He appears overwhelmed and underqualified. As such, he usually appears dazzled by the fame, style, and/or sheer brilliance of the criminal he is stalking.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__129">Of course, he is none of these things. His style is very studiously chosen. He frequently asks to use the restroom, a very humanizing touch calculated to put the criminal at ease. We often hear of his wife, but never hear her name. As far as we know, her first name is &#x201C;Mrs.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__129">At the surface level, Columbo appears incompetent. Just to be clear, we do not for a moment suggest that one should adopt an appearance and demeanor of incompetence. But consider what is going on just one level below the surface.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__129">Columbo uses his style to eradicate a preconception, thereby setting the other party at ease. This is his genius, and this is what an advisor must emulate. Consider the typical client, who is sometimes intimidated by the technical expertise of the advisor, which by definition far exceeds his own. A common client feeling (however unconscious) is one of &#x201C;you expert, me dummy.&#x201D; This sends out psychological echoes many levels deep. Those echoes may include resentment, awe, jealousy, identification, competition, desire to be liked, and so on.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">On top of that, the client approaches typically with a problem, an issue that is troubling and that needs solving. So there are things at stake, either costs or potential benefits, things to be lost or things yet to be gained. This produces yet another level of psychological echoes, a sense of criticality, of impending something.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">Finally, there are the trappings of the meeting. The framed degree behind the advisor&#x2019;s desk, the white lab coat, the latest electronic business toy, the thumb-worn copy of the Official Airline Guide. These are all visible symbols that reinforce the sense of one&#x2019;s fate being in the hands of another.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">Columbo knows all this, and punctures it neatly. He praises the &#x201C;client&#x2019;s&#x201D; intelligence. He wears the anti-uniform. He makes small talk. He dismisses the seriousness of his capabilities. And one by one, the &#x201C;client&#x2019;s&#x201D; inhibitions and concerns begin to vanish.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">In this environment, Columbo is ready to go to work. The &#x201C;client&#x201D; is now willing to talk openly and honestly. He begins to describe things as he perceives them and not as he wants others to perceive them. Information is offered rather than withheld. Personalities emerge for what they are. And progress toward resolution can be made.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">On one level, Columbo&#x2019;s lesson is obvious. Set the client at ease and don&#x2019;t overwhelm him with technical expertise. But part of Columbo&#x2019;s fascination for us is that it is not easy, at all, to emulate him. What are the obstacles to Columbo-based consulting?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">The biggest barrier is our own love, as advisors, for all the things that put the client on guard. The degrees, the uniforms, and the other trappings of our professions signify success: We worked hard, extremely hard, to get where we got and, by golly, what&#x2019;s wrong with a little discrete demonstration of our status?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">If we can overcome that need for ego gratification, another big barrier appears. That is, of course, the belief that our success is exclusively about technical mastery. So we behave in anti-Columbo ways by continually nodding sagely, and interpolating pieces of knowledgeable wisdom (the professional equivalent of namedropping.) We listen with our noses high, until we deign to descend with the almighty Answer (or so it can seem to our clients). Don&#x2019;t forget, many of our clients believe in this game as well; at least until they are faced with something better.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">The biggest barrier to capitalizing on Columbo&#x2019;s wisdom, then, is once again found through Pogo&#x2019;s dictum: We have found the enemy, and it is us. It is our own inability to act upon the so-called marketing principle, that we should focus on our clients and their problems exclusively, and not letting our own personalities, needs and, images get in the way.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">Columbo&#x2019;s genius lies in neutralizing expectations about himself. He is not a trickster; he is the anti-trickster. He is not an illusionist; he is the one who strips away illusions. He becomes the professional equivalent of beige, of background music. He subordinates his ego to the service of the client.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__130">And, of course, he always wins.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
