<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch13.html#ch13">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__97">13</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__97">Envisioning an Alternate Reality</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__97">E</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__97">NVISIONING IS THE FOURTH STAGE</Run>
          <Run Tag="__97"> in the process of trust creation, after engaging, listening, and framing.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">As noted in Chapter 9, where we began to present the five-stage process, the role of joint envisioning in the trust-development process is to concretize a specific vision and choice among the many future states toward which the client might want to aim. In envisioning, the advisor and the client jointly imagine what the end result might look like, addressing the questions:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Decimal" Margin="48,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__97">For what are we </Run>
            <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">really</Run>
            <Run Tag="__97"> aiming here?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__97">What will it look like when we get there?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__97">How will we know we are there?</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">Of the five stages, envisioning is the one most often neglected. Sales models, for example, may go straight from problem definition to action and solution. To some extent, focusing on benefits is parallel to what we call envisioning; but it is not the same thing.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">The language of politics offers us some &#x201C;sound-bite-sized&#x201D; examples of envisioning, and hints at its value. Consider the New Deal, the New Frontier, the Great Society, or Martin Luther King&#x2019;s &#x201C;I Have a Dream&#x201D; speech.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__97">These are all attempts to articulate, in a succinct way, the essence of something for which to aim, and something that actually </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">could be</Run>
          <Run Tag="__97"> attained with real effort. They have a tremendous impact on the building of energy and consensus by articulating a goal (and a way of thinking about that goal).</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">Envisioning is what we tried to do with you in Chapter 1, the Sneak Preview. We asked you to imagine what it would be like to be trusted by your clients, and whether you wanted those benefits. We also asked you to think about what your role would look like if you were a trusted advisor.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">Successful envisioning in a business frees up people. It takes them far out of the technical, problem-solving, high-risk perspective with which they approach most problem solving, and into a new perspective. This new perspective is one that encourages freedom and creativity. Of all the steps in trust creation, it is the one that isn&#x2019;t absolutely necessary but can often add the greatest value.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__97">United Research, a consulting firm that later became part of Gemini Consulting, made great use of this step in the 1980s and early 1990s. They employed a multistep sales process, including listening and diagnostic steps, but their key step was a large-scale exercise in envisioning.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">They would interact with large numbers of people and ask them a series of leading questions. They would ask:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">&#x201C;Could things be different around here? If so, could they be better? How? In what ways? What would things look like in this better future? What would have to change for that to happen? Where would the benefits show up?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">As people spent time on this envisioning step, they began to articulate in great detail just how things might look in a world where the major problem facing them had been solved, or the major opportunity in front of them had been attained. The idea rapidly took hold that real change could be accomplished and might be worth working for. Suddenly it was no longer abstract. It was real, and possible. And suddenly it was no longer scary. It was both energizing (&#x201C;Let&#x2019;s go for it&#x201D;) and comforting (&#x201C;We can do this&#x201D;).</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">This outcome is identical to what can happen in a two-person, relationship-building, trust-based conversation. By jointly focusing on a mutually attractive future, unencumbered by the problems of the present, barriers can be broken down and bridges can be built.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">After successful listening and framing, there is a huge temptation to omit envisioning and to get to the next step (commitment and taking action), but it is a temptation worth resisting.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">Grammar is a good guide here. Instead of using the words &#x201C;why don&#x2019;t we?&#x201D; at this stage, substitute the words &#x201C;how would things be if . . .&#x201D; Focus on descriptive sentences. Ask questions about things like benefits, end states, or outcomes.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__98">An Illustration</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">Charlie had a client, Mark, who was extremely frustrated with a work situation. He had taken on an assignment, as a consultant, for the CEO of an existing client, despite an already heavy workload. While the assignment carried with it some risk of failure, the CEO assured Mark of his personal interest in the project and his intention to be fully available when necessary. Mark&#x2019;s primary contact was to be the chief operating officer.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">A short time later, the chief operating officer experienced some severe personal difficulties and asked that Mark work with another executive. That person was goodwilled but often unknowledgeable and ineffective. After a time, Mark raised this issue with the CEO, but little changed as a result of this conversation.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">As time passed, matters deteriorated; the CEO continued to be even less available, as did the chief operating officer, but there was no lessening of pressure to deliver results on the project. Predictably, Mark was upset and frustrated.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__98">When Charlie first talked to him, Mark&#x2019;s way of framing the issue was:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__99">&#x201C;The client is being very unfair to me: I took on some considerable risk based on his personal assurance of open access, but find that he is not delivering on his part of the bargain.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__99">This instinctive way of framing the issue is perfectly understandable and natural, but nonetheless quite inappropriate. First, it is entirely about Mark, not the client. Second, it is loaded with speculative attributions of motive on the part of the client. Finally, it is judgmental.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__99">Mark and Charlie worked together to reframe the issue by focusing more on the client, by removing the tone of blame, and by striving for objectivity rather than judgment. A step along the way sounded more like:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__99">&#x201C;I am upset because the client is not spending the time with me that I expected, thus jeopardizing the quality of the work.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__99">However, this statement still suffers from self-focus, blame, and judgment. As they worked further, they agreed that a useful framing of the problem had to take into account the client&#x2019;s point of view. Not knowing his position, they had to hypothesize about it, as follows:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__99">&#x201C;Things have gotten busy. As a result, he hasn&#x2019;t been able to provide the time he had hoped to commit, which means he is in a position of having to do other than what he had promised. And I find myself in a position of possibly producing lower quality than I had promised. Neither of us is happy with the situation.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__99">Based on this revised framing, Mark decided to try envisioning with his CEO client. He began the conversation as follows:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__99">&#x201C;Look, Albert, before we both jump to even more commitments we both might regret, can we take a minute and be sure we&#x2019;re in sync about what&#x2019;s at stake? What are we trying to accomplish? How will we know when we&#x2019;ve got it right?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__100">Finally, they generated a picture of what might be, envisioning a different future, sounding something like:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__100">&#x201C;If we settled on a common view of where we&#x2019;re going, we&#x2019;d be able to table an issue until we had time to talk about it, instead of worrying about what the delay meant. We&#x2019;d know that a delay wasn&#x2019;t personal. We&#x2019;d know that quality is always a variable, and that all decisions have impact. We&#x2019;d raise issues more quickly. We wouldn&#x2019;t wait until crises came up. We wouldn&#x2019;t interpret events solely as personal failures or successes, but sometimes just as events. We&#x2019;d have an agreed-upon formula, if not a schedule, that we both understood and could rely on. We wouldn&#x2019;t lose sleep worrying. We&#x2019;d have confidence in each other.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__100">Mark obtained the cooperation he needed to serve his client by getting him to envision the benefits of the future state.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__100">Summary</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__100">It is very tempting to leave out the envisioning activity, and to slip into action language directly from framing. The client, in fact, is every bit as likely to say, after the problem has been defined, &#x201C;Well, what can we do about this?&#x201D; And the words &#x201C;what can we do&#x201D; are like a Pavlovian bell to many advisors: We feel we must respond because our self-image as technical masters is on the line.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__100">How much better it is to be able to say, &#x201C;Hold on, we&#x2019;ll get there, but let&#x2019;s first spend some time talking about where it is we want to go, and what it is we&#x2019;re really trying to achieve.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__100">With a clear understanding of the destination, both parties to the conversation will have articulated just what is at stake, they will have signed up for the benefits, and they will both also have started the outline, the specifications, for what an eventual solution might look like. Having had such a conversation, they are now far better primed to talk about &#x201C;what to do about it.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
