<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch6.html#ch6">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__50">6</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__50">The Importance of Mindsets</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__50">S</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__50">O FAR</Run>
          <Run Tag="__50">, </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__50">WE HAVE EXAMINED</Run>
          <Run Tag="__50"> three skills: earning trust, giving advice, and building relationships. Skills alone will not accomplish the task, however. In addition, a trusted advisor must develop appropriate attitudes or &#x201C;mindsets.&#x201D; The most important of these are:</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Decimal" Margin="48,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__50">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__50">Ability to focus on the other person</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__50">Self-confidence</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__50">Ego strength</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__50">Curiosity</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__50">Inclusive professionalism</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__50">Focus on the Other Person</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__50">This attitude (or mindset) is summed up in the aphorism: &#x201C;You&#x2019;ll have more fun and success by focusing on helping other people achieve their goals than you will by focusing on your own goals.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__50">For some this sounds like an idealistic, spiritual, or religious principle. Others may think of it as communism: a cry to place others before yourself. A moment&#x2019;s reflection, however, will reveal that the aphorism is the very definition of what a capitalist exchange economy is about. To get what you want from someone, you must first focus on giving them what they want!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__50">As Dale Carnegie said, &#x201C;The only way to influence someone is to find out what they want, and show them how to get it.&#x201D; Notice that Carnegie did not say &#x201C;the best way to influence&#x201D; but &#x201C;the only way&#x201D;!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__50">Tim&#x2019;s Story</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__50">Charlie once observed Tim White (then publisher of the </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__50">Albany Times Union</Run>
          <Run Tag="__50">, later of the </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__50">San Francisco Examiner</Run>
          <Run Tag="__50">) run an offsite meeting of his management team of a dozen people. Throughout this meeting, Tim conveyed a sense of technical mastery, calm, and wisdom. Yet he did so by hardly ever expressing an opinion, making a technical point, or articulating a decision. Instead, almost all of his input consisted of visually and verbally scanning the table, seeking emotional expressions on the faces of his team.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__50">&#x201C;Joe, you don&#x2019;t agree with that, do you?&#x201D; he might say, or &#x201C;Bob, you&#x2019;ve got some pretty strong feelings about this one, don&#x2019;t you?&#x201D; The meeting was highly successful. Not only were decisions made, but everyone felt involved and consulted and that the process was &#x201C;fair.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">Tim did not lack for technical competence, and he had strong opinions, but he achieved most of his ends by devoting his attention almost entirely to observing, understanding, and articulating the needs of others. He achieved high-content results almost entirely through low-content leadership.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">It is this ability to stay focused on other people, in the face of a swirling set of demanding distractions, that is so problematic for many of us. Success at being other-focused is not a function of formal business tools but of personal psychology.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__51">Impediments to Being Client-Focused</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__51">The prime obstacle to focusing successfully on the other person (in our experience) is the apparently common belief that mastery of technical content is sufficient to serve clients well. It is ironic that a business in which the serving of clients depends so heavily on interpersonal psychology should be peopled with those who believe in the </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">exclusive</Run>
          <Run Tag="__51"> power of technical mastery.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">And yet, as David Nadler, CEO of Delta Consulting, puts it:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">&#x201C;The truth is, you can fix the content thing better than you can fix the collaborative thing. For some people with process consulting backgrounds, content can be tough. But in general you can train for content better than you can for collaboration.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">Another major obstacle is the inability to focus concentrated attention on the client. In the midst of a conversation with a client, we are likely to find ourselves with thoughts like, &#x201C;How will I solve this problem?&#x201D; &#x201C;How will I get the client to buy this idea?&#x201D; &#x201C;What am I going to say when the client finishes talking?&#x201D; &#x201C;How can I appear expert?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">If we are honest and strip down all these distractions to the core, we are likely to find some form of fear at the root. It may be fear of embarrassment, of failure, of appearing ignorant or incompetent, or fear of loss of reputation or security.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">Ironically, the professions attract people who are prone to these fears. More often than not, we professionals are high achievers who have consistently overcome our fears through constant application of skill and hard work in the pursuit of technical mastery. And, up to a point, these things are rewarded. In the early levels of professional life, we are often asked to focus on little else.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__51">Then comes that crucial career transition, from technician to full professional, from content expert to advisor. As technicians, our task is to provide information, analyses, research, content, and even recommendations. All of these are basically tasks performed out of the client&#x2019;s presence. In contrast, our task as advisors is an &#x201C;in-person,&#x201D; &#x201C;in-contact&#x201D; challenge to help the client see things anew or to make a decision. This requires a complete change of skills and mindsets.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">It can be unsettling to find that the client is primarily interested in having his or her problem understood, in all its emotional and political complexity, as a precondition to having the problem diagnosed and solved.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">Some of us never make it through this hurdle. The key to prior career success (technical excellence) can actually become an impediment at this level. Then, the fears, which drove us to excellence in the first place, reemerge.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__52">The kinds of people who typically succeed in professional service firms are often driven, rational, and meritocratic, with a great need to achieve. It is the natural thing for such people to stay focused on their own individual performance (something that is reinforced by many firm cultures), and to look for confirmation that what </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">they</Run>
          <Run Tag="__52"> are doing is all right. This is not a situation conducive to building skills in developing trust. It is in some sense a wonder that so many do so well.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">Listen to what Stephanie Wethered, an Episcopal priest, has to say:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">&#x201C;The key is empathetic listening. It&#x2019;s vital in the pastoral world. It involves the willingness to go to where the other person is, which is usually a very painful place. And you have to be in touch with your own pain to go there. If you don&#x2019;t know that pain, that terrain, you will not go there. It&#x2019;s about moving from &#x2018;I&#x2019; to &#x2018;We.&#x2019; &#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">Empathetic listening is a critical skill. And our ability to do it well, according to Stephanie, is in direct relation to how closely we can truly feel what the other person feels. Our ability to do that is in direct relation to how well we can leave behind our own self-orientation and our desire for self-promotion.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">Charlie was reminded of this recently. He had started with a new client, referred in by another consultant. Charlie had fun preparing for the first conference call with the CEO, but he also spent some significant time wondering and worrying about how he was going to come across to the CEO.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">As Charlie discussed the call later with the consultant who had referred him in, she said that she had spoken with the CEO and that he had asked, &#x201C;Does Charlie like the project? Did he like me?&#x201D; It was a reminder that, to a great extent, we all are overfocused on ourselves. Charlie&#x2019;s orientation was to himself; the client&#x2019;s was, too.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">Learning to focus on the other isn&#x2019;t an instantaneous decision: it&#x2019;s a lifelong learning experience!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__52">Self-Confidence</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__52">Insecurity (the opposite of self-confidence) is a common source of trust problems. We have already noted the common temptation, in a client conversation, of jumping too soon to &#x201C;the answer.&#x201D; It is only human for the client to want to be understood before being ready to listen to advice. We </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__52">know</Run>
          <Run Tag="__52"> that, but it takes self-confidence to wait and believe that after listening and brainstorming, we will still have ample time and talent to discover the technical answer.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__53">We are not talking about monumental levels of self-confidence here. It is sufficient to simply be able to focus our finite attention on listening and understanding, without believing we must squander it all immediately on problem solving.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__53">Ego Strength</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__53">Ego strength is not the same as self-confidence. It is the ability to focus on the consultative relationship process, rather than on credit or blame attached to the search. There is an old saying, &#x201C;It is amazing what you can achieve if you are not wedded to who gets the credit.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__53">The flip side of credit is blame. A tendency to blame others, or circumstances, is generally a recipe for unhappiness in life. It is even more surely and quickly a recipe for failure in becoming a trusted advisor. Clients (and professional firms) place a great deal of value on those who take on great amounts of personal responsibility.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__53">However, taking responsibility can become dysfunctional as well. Charlie once retained a psychologist to administer and interpret tests of successful and unsuccessful consultants. The results served mainly to distinguish each group from the population at large, by the huge amount of &#x201C;responsibility taking&#x201D; evidenced by the consultants. She explained: &#x201D;These are people who would feel personally responsible for the weather if it rained on the corporate picnic.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__53">At this level, what would appear to be the opposite of blaming becomes clear for what it is: merely another form of self-orientation. Just as wanting all the credit and none of the blame is self-focused, so is taking </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__53">all</Run>
          <Run Tag="__53"> the responsibility. Neither is client-focused.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__53">Joe Sherman, the managing director of San Francisco&#x2019;s Fidelity Partners, describes what ego strength in an advisor meant for him.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__53">&#x201C;I had a huge ethical disagreement with someone, which had come to a head. I had brought along (my advisor) and he was listening to the tirades of this other person, and he was able to just listen. I was so emotionally attached that I couldn&#x2019;t let go. I could barely contain my anger. But (my advisor) was calm and direct, and didn&#x2019;t engage in the venom. He was able to steer the discussion to where it needed to go. Since then, that advisor has handled all my business and personal matters.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__53">Ego strength allows one to focus on the matter at hand, and not on who gets blame or credit for getting there.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__53">Curiosity</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__54">The right to solve problems is earned by informed listening, which in turn is driven by curiosity.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__54">The key is to focus not on what we know, but on what we don&#x2019;t know. And that is curiosity: the constant asking of questions. &#x201C;What&#x2019;s behind that?&#x201D; &#x201C;Why is this the case?&#x201D; &#x201C;How does this fit in?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__54">As curiosity does its work, problem definitions evolve. Patterns emerge, connections are made, and positions soften and re-form. Perspectives migrate, and richness of insight is gained. The &#x201C;right answer&#x201D; is never as right at the outset as it is after it has evolved, informed by inquiry. Curiosity is the attitude that drives the opportunity to contribute.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__54">Inclusive Professionalism</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__54">Many professionals view professionalism as something that sets them apart from the client. There are &#x201C;business people&#x201D; and then there are &#x201C;professionals.&#x201D; There are &#x201C;corporations,&#x201D; and then there are &#x201C;professional firms.&#x201D; Many professional firms work hard to create the sense that professionals, or the professions, are in some way separate, different, or apart. We think this is incorrect, dangerous, and self-defeating. The essence of professionalism lies not in distinguishing ourselves from our clients, but in aligning with them to improve their situations.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__54">The attitude of exclusive professionalism (which restricts the label of professionalism to the advisor) manifests itself in a number of dysfunctional ways. It reinforces a misleading belief that the advisor&#x2019;s job is to solve problems rather than to help the client solve problems. It reinforces a belief that advisors must &#x201C;control&#x201D; or &#x201C;manage&#x201D; client interactions and relationships, as opposed to inhabiting them jointly.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__54">Inclusive professionalism means acknowledging and engaging the professionalism of others. It means that the unique talents of each party should be brought to bear jointly for the greater good. It means joint responsibility for the effectiveness of work.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__54">Whatever the reason, many of us in the professions are not very good at teamwork. Many of us collaborate very poorly, even with each other. Small wonder, then, that we don&#x2019;t always collaborate well with clients.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__54">Most firms </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__54">say</Run>
          <Run Tag="__54"> they support inclusive professionalism, but we have found that conclusion, in many cases, to be somewhat self-deluding. We know consulting firms whose policy it is to not leave behind written materials, for fear that the consulting firm might &#x201C;lose control.&#x201D; We know law firms that have strict policies on what &#x201C;work product&#x201D; clients may see, outlining an essentially adversarial relationship from the start. All these practices are largely based on an &#x201C;us versus them&#x201D; concept, rather than the &#x201C;us&#x201D; implied by inclusive professionalism.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
