<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="9780743205443_ch3.html#ch3">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,80,0,28" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="16">
        <Run Tag="__26">3</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Center" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16">
            <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19" Tag="__26">Earning Trust</Run>
          </Span>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        <LineBreak/>
        <LineBreak/>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="16" Tag="__26">T</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" Tag="__26">O</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" xml:space="preserve" Tag="__26"> SEE HOW</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" xml:space="preserve" Tag="__26"> THE</Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="11" xml:space="preserve" Tag="__26"> SUCCESS</Run>
          <Run Tag="__26"> of your professional career depends on trust, consider your own purchases of professional services. Whether you are hiring someone to look after your legal affairs, your taxes, your child, or your car, the act of retaining a professional requires you to put your affairs in someone else&#x2019;s hands. You are forced into an act of faith, and you can only hope that they will deal with you appropriately.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">You can research their background, check their technical skills, and attempt to examine their past performance. In spite of all this, when the final decision on whom to hire comes, you must ultimately decide to trust someone with your baby, which is never a comfortable thing to do.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">When retaining a professional, what you (and your clients) want is someone who understands your interests and will not put their interests ahead of yours while working for you. You want someone you can trust to do the right thing. You want someone who will care. Getting hired (and getting rehired) is about earning and deserving that trust.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__26">How to Win Trust</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">If trust is so important, how does one go about winning it? How do you get somebody to trust you? It is clear that it is not done by saying &#x201C;Trust me!&#x201D; Nothing is more likely to get the listener to put up his or her defenses!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__26">The key point is that trust must be </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">earned</Run>
          <Run Tag="__26"> and </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">deserved.</Run>
          <Run Tag="__26"> You must do something to give the other people the evidence on which they can base their decision on whether to trust you. You must be willing to </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">give</Run>
          <Run Tag="__26"> in order to </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">get.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">For example, David (Maister) once had to hire a lawyer to probate a relative&#x2019;s will. The first few lawyers he spoke with tried to win his business by telling him when their firm was founded, how many offices they had, and how much they would charge. None of this inspired much confidence. In fact, the more they talked about themselves and their firms, the less interested they appeared to be in David and his problems.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">Finally, he encountered a lawyer who, in the initial phone call, asked how much David knew about probating a will. David&#x2019;s reply was &#x201C;Nothing!&#x201D; The lawyer then offered to fax to David a comprehensive outline of the steps involved, what he needed to do immediately, and what he should forget about for a while because it was not urgent. The fax also provided the phone numbers of all the governmental bodies David needed to notify, even though this had nothing to do with the legal work (or the lawyer&#x2019;s fees).</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__26">All of this (immensely helpful) information was provided freely (and for free) before the lawyer had been retained. Naturally, he got the business. He had built confidence by demonstrating that he knew what information was most relevant to David, even though some of it had nothing to with the practice of estate law. He had earned trust by being generous with his knowledge and proving that he was willing to earn the potential client&#x2019;s business.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">Trust can be earned by the simplest of gestures. David has a dentist, named Andrew, who, early in the relationship, recommended that David permit him to perform various procedures on his teeth. Like many clients, David was not sure whether Andrew was recommending additional procedures because they were really needed or because he was just trying to increase his revenues (i.e., cross-selling).</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__27">David&#x2019;s view of Andrew was significantly affected by the fact that every time David (or his wife, Kathy) went to his office, Andrew </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">always</Run>
          <Run Tag="__27"> telephoned later that evening (without fail) to ask whether he (or she) was in pain, whether a prescription was needed, and so on. David and Kathy were very impressed by this. Andrew was acting as if he cared; unusual behavior for a dentist!</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">At first, David and Kathy were a little cynical. Did he care, or was he just acting &#x201C;as if&#x201D; he cared? Had he been to a dental marketing course, or read a client relations book? They didn&#x2019;t know. Over time, however, as Andrew&#x2019;s small gestures continued and accumulated, they came to believe that he was sincere. Today, they usually accept his recommendations for additional work. They have come to trust him.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__27">Charlie and the Sandpaper</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">Soon after Charlie (Green) had been promoted to a managerial position in a consulting firm, he got a promising sales lead with a manufacturer of abrasives. His firm, like all consulting firms, valued those who could bring in new business, and he was eager to make his mark. He set up an appointment with the prospective client and invited a senior partner to join him on the call.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">He and the partner were shown into the client&#x2019;s office, where they shook hands, accepted coffee, slid business cards across the conference table, all the while chatting and probing for points of connection and mutual interest: friends in common, shared experiences or backgrounds, similar attitudes toward life or business.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">When they at last turned to the business at hand, the client focused his full attention on Charlie, and asked: &#x201C;Now, what experience does your firm have in doing marketing studies for industrial consumables?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__27">In an instant, Charlie&#x2019;s mind seemed to have been sucked dry. He had no idea what was meant by </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">industrial consumables</Run>
          <Run Tag="__27">. Then, a revelatory thought popped into his mind: the man is talking about </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">sandpaper!</Run>
          <Run Tag="__27"> But that knowledge only served to deepen Charlie&#x2019;s fear. He was sure that his firm had not done any such studies.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">Charlie felt sure that if he told the client the truth, he could not win the business and would probably spend the rest of his career at his firm in leg irons and public shame. In the next millisecond, his training as a consultant kicked in, and he began formulating (in his mind) an answer.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__27">&#x201C;Not exactly,&#x201D; he planned to say, &#x201C;but we have done many marketing studies, some of them for products quite similar to industrial consumables.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">What products might be quite similar to industrial consumables, he would figure out later.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">But, just as Charlie drew breath to speak, his senior partner leaned forward. He looked directly at the client, and said,</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">&#x201C;None that I can think of.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">He paused for a long moment. Then he looked the client in the eye, and continued:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">&#x201C;Given that, is there anything else that you think it would be helpful to discuss?&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">The client looked unconcerned and then asked what similar experience the firm had that might be relevant. They proceeded with their pitch.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__28">Had Charlie given </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">his</Run>
          <Run Tag="__28"> answer, it would have sacrificed his credibility and revealed his own focus on self-interest. It would have signaled to the client that he was willing to fudge his credentials. Who would trust such a person?</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">The answer the senior partner gave contained quite a different subtext. It said:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">&#x201C;I will answer your questions, directly and truthfully, even if it means losing a chance at your business.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">In that moment, Charlie learned two important things about building trust. First, it has to do with keeping one&#x2019;s self-interest in check, and, second, trust can be won or lost very rapidly.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__28">Charlie&#x2019;s firm won the business. He was not placed in leg irons. And he learned a lot about sandpaper.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__28">A Lawyer&#x2019;s Moment of Truth</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">Peter Biagetti is a senior litigator at the prestigious Boston law firm of Mintz, Levin, Cohn, Ferris, Glovsky and Popeo.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">A property developer who wished to sue his own mother, a partner in the family real estate business, had hired Biagetti to represent him. Biagetti got ready for the case, and a court date was set.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">Just before the first hearing, Biagetti met the developer on the steps of the courthouse. The developer seemed to hesitate, his body language suggesting indecision, reluctance, and some kind of discomfort. Biagetti saw a man who was wrestling with a dozen issues that had to do with family pride, personal success, recognition, and filial love.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">He knew that the lawsuit could resolve only one issue, and a relatively minor one at that. Drawing on the common background he shared with his client, he decided to comment on what he saw. &#x201C;I told him that I found it hard to imagine how it must feel to go into litigation with his mother. I said I didn&#x2019;t think it was something many sons could go through with.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">The developer might have upbraided his lawyer, told him to mind his own business, just do his job and get on with it. But he didn&#x2019;t. Instead, he stopped and looked at Biagetti. The developer decided not to press the lawsuit. Biagetti commented later: &#x201C;I think he respected that we&#x2019;d girded for battle, but were not so bellicose as to want to crush his mother. We settled the matter on the court-house steps.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">Soon after the settlement, the developer sent more work to Biagetti&#x2019;s firm, and eventually he decided to use Mintz, Levin for all of his business and family legal needs.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">Another lawyer might not have sensed his client&#x2019;s underlying concerns, been blind to his courthouse hesitation, been unwilling to forgo the revenues of a potentially lucrative trial, or (most important of all) not felt enough affinity for him to speak up. But in this case, the client drew back a curtain and the lawyer was willing to look through the window. This is how a trusted advisor relationship often begins.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">Not all of us will notice when an unusual opportunity has been revealed. Nor will we all have the quickness or confidence to respond to it. But if we have listened well, observed accurately, and spoken truthfully (and if there exists a degree of personal affinity), the client may welcome the expansion of the conversation. He (or she) may, in fact, take the opportunity to throw the window open yet wider still, revealing to the professional all manner of issues and concerns, aspirations and fears.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">As in most things, however, timing is all. A successful advisor knows when to bother a client, and when not to. Alan Schwartz, of the Canadian law firm Fasken Martineau Dumoulin, notes:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="32,0,32,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__29">&#x201C;Clients are busy people and don&#x2019;t want to be interrupted with unimportant questions or barraged with requests for information or lengthy reports on matters that they consider to be an unwarranted intrusion on their time. Many years ago, a client called to report that they were very pleased with the lawyer that I had referred to them for a specific matter. His comment was, &#x2018;He knew exactly when to bother me and when to leave me alone.&#x2019;&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__29">Some Insights on Trust</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">How can we increase trust? Can we become more trustworthy?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">To answer these questions, it helps to note some characteristics of trust. Specifically, it:</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <List MarkerStyle="Decimal" Margin="48,32,0,32" TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__30">Grows, rather than just appears</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__30">Is both rational and emotional</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__30">Presumes a two-way relationship</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__30">Is intrinsically about perceived risk</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__30">Is different for the client than it is for the advisor</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
        <ListItem TextAlignment="Left" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Paragraph>
            <Run Tag="__30">Is personal</Run>
          </Paragraph>
        </ListItem>
      </List>
      <Paragraph Margin="16,24,0,8" TextAlignment="Left" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__30">Trust Grows</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__30">Trust rarely develops instantly, except in the face of a powerful experience. This may seem unremarkable until we note that other feelings develop much more quickly. We may say, immediately after meeting someone, that we like him (or that we don&#x2019;t). We draw similarly fast conclusions about whether we respect someone, or are bored by them. And we may very quickly say, &#x201C;I </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">don&#x2019;t</Run>
          <Run Tag="__30"> trust him.&#x201D;</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">What we don&#x2019;t usually say quickly is, &#x201C;I trust her.&#x201D; Instead, we may say &#x201C;She seems like the kind of person I could come to trust,&#x201D; or &#x201C;I might trust her,&#x201D; or &#x201C;She seems to be trustworthy.&#x201D; Actual trust, as our language shows, is usually withheld, pending further evidence.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">The fact is that trust does not happen without work, without volition, or without effort. It is not handed to us on a platter. Although we will later provide many suggestions, hot tips, and quick-impact actions, it must always be borne in mind that trust results from accumulated experiences, over time. There is no quick fix.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="16,24,0,8" TextAlignment="Left" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__30">Trust Is both Rational and Emotional</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">Second, trust straddles the ground between the rational and the emotional. On the one hand, trust is based on direct experience of the expertise brought to bear on the client&#x2019;s problems. Content-free advisors are soon identified and rejected. On the other hand, as we saw in Chapter 1, we value trusted advisors for their support, their dedication to our interests, their courage in challenging us (with delicacy), and other emotional factors. As an exercise, go back to that chapter and divide the traits of trusted advisors listed there into rational categories and emotional categories. You may be surprised at what you find!</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__30">The significance of this for anyone in business who needs to deal with trusted relationships is profound. Much of business is transacted &#x201C;as if&#x201D; it were all in the rational realm. This is, perhaps, nowhere more true than in professional services. In our experience, there are many professionals who are </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">offended</Run>
          <Run Tag="__30"> at the thought that their relationships and their client effectiveness might be based on something other than pure technical competence.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__30">Yet this is only half the story. While outstanding technical competence (or content) is a nonnegotiable, essential ingredient for success, it is not </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__30">sufficient.</Run>
          <Run Tag="__30"> Trust is a lot richer than logic alone, and it is a significant component of success.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="16,24,0,8" TextAlignment="Left" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__31">Trust Is a Two-Way Relationship</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">Third, trust is a two-way relationship. One can love, or hate, or respect, or be fascinated by someone else, without the other person doing or thinking the same, or being in any way involved in the first person&#x2019;s activity. The same is not true for trust.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">While there are things you can do to improve your trustworthiness, you do not have the ability to create a trusted advisor relationship on your own. Your client must participate and reciprocate. This means that you may have to select carefully those with whom you wish to build a trusted advisor relationship. No amount of interaction will add up to trust, if the efforts are all unilateral. You can&#x2019;t force trust.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">The trusted advisor relationship takes place between two individuals and is highly personal. It involves emotion as well as intellect. It is dynamic and fluid. Building a trusted advisor relationship involves not only straightforward discussion, rigorous decision making, and conventional consultation, but also moments of revelation, late-night inspirations, odd actions of connection, and moments of epiphany.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="16,24,0,8" TextAlignment="Left" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__31">Trust Entails Risk</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__31">Trust without risk is like cola without fizz; there isn&#x2019;t much point to it. If party A trusts that party B will do something, it means that party B (1) </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">could</Run>
          <Run Tag="__31"> do something different, (2) conceivably </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">might</Run>
          <Run Tag="__31"> do something different; but (3) because of the relationship, most likely </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">won&#x2019;t</Run>
          <Run Tag="__31"> do something different.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">If party B couldn&#x2019;t and wouldn&#x2019;t do other than what party A expects, then the relationship would be just about probabilities and capabilities, not about trust.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__31">The potential of trust violation is always there in a trusting relationship. The choice on the part of the advisor </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">not</Run>
          <Run Tag="__31"> to violate that trust is what makes the relationship special.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">The levels of risk may, of course, vary from case to case. The risk of choosing the wrong attorney to assist a CEO in a multibillion dollar merger is very different from that same CEO&#x2019;s choice of a lawyer to prepare his or her will. The former is career threatening. However, while the latter may have less money at stake, it will usually still involve a perceived risk (and hence a need for trust) that is nontrivial.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">When first encountering some of the trust-enhancing techniques we discuss in this book, many people are likely to say, &#x201C;But that&#x2019;s risky.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">They usually overstate the degree of risk, but at root they are correct. Creating trust entails taking some personal risks. It is the essence of trust. If you&#x2019;re not a little scared on occasion, then you&#x2019;re not taking a risk. And if you&#x2019;re not taking a risk, you&#x2019;re not likely to create trust.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="16,24,0,8" TextAlignment="Left" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__31">Trust Is Different for the Client and the Advisor</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">Two people who love each other share the experience of love. One may love more or less than the other, and their degree of loving may vary from time to time, but the thing that they are doing (loving) is in essence the same.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">This is not true for trust. In trust, one does the trusting, and one is trusted. The roles are not the same. Trust is more like ballroom dancing. One person must lead and one must follow, if it is going to work. If there is ambiguity about who is leading and who is following, then the dance collapses into (at best) two parallel exercises in solo movement.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__31">This characteristic of trust has an interesting implication. Just because you can trust does not mean you can be trusted. However, if you are incapable of trusting, you probably can&#x2019;t be trusted. The ability to trust someone else is a necessary, though not a sufficient, condition for being trustworthy.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph Margin="16,24,0,8" TextAlignment="Left" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="12">
        <Run Tag="__32">Trust Is Personal</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">Years ago, Texaco Oil ran a TV advertising campaign with a song whose lyrics went, &#x201C;You can trust your car to the man who wears the star, the big, bright Texaco star.&#x201D; Perhaps times have become more cynical, but we doubt such a campaign would be aired today. And even then, the song said it was not the star we should trust, but the man wearing it.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">The truth is, &#x201C;institutional trust&#x201D; is an oxymoron. We don&#x2019;t trust institutions, we don&#x2019;t trust processes, we trust people. We may come to believe that a given institution&#x2019;s behaviors are highly predictable, that most or all of its people can be depended upon to behave in certain ways. We may thus associate trusted people with a given institution. But we are still trusting a person and not giving blanket trust to a particular institution.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">Trust requires being understood and having some capacity to act upon that understanding. Organizations per se are incapable of understanding; only their people can do so. Brand name recognition and reputation may get an institution on anyone&#x2019;s short list, but only a person can keep it there.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">It follows that if trust plays a role for professional service firms, then it will find its voice not in advertising campaigns or in citations of experience or credentials, but in the human interactions between those firms&#x2019; people and their clients.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__32">In this sense, the movie </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">The Godfather</Run>
          <Run Tag="__32"> had it wrong when it said, &#x201C;It ain&#x2019;t personal, it&#x2019;s business.&#x201D; The truth is, &#x201C;It&#x2019;s business; it </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">is</Run>
          <Run Tag="__32"> personal.&#x201D;</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">At its core, trust is about relationships. I will trust you if I believe that you&#x2019;re in this for the long haul, that you&#x2019;re not just trying to maximize the short-term benefit to you in each of our interactions. Trust is about reciprocity: you help me and I&#x2019;ll help you. But I need to know that I can rely on you to do your part, and that our relationship is built upon shared values and principles.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">If I am the client, then trusting you requires that I can believe you will do what you say you will do, that your actions will match your words.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
        <Span FontStyle="Normal" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14">
          <Run Tag="__32">And, perhaps most critical of all, I will trust you if you exhibit some form of caring, if you provide some evidence that </Run>
          <Run FontStyle="Italic" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="14" Tag="__32">my</Run>
          <Run Tag="__32"> interests are as important to you as your own interests are.</Run>
        </Span>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
