<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section Margin="24,16,24,16" BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Paragraph/>
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="OEBPS/Brow_9780385533133_epub_c67_r1.htm#c67">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,17,0,18" TextAlignment="Right" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontSize="19">
        <Run FontFamily="sans-serif" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="19" Tag="__312">CHAPTER</Run>
        <Run FontFamily="sans-serif" FontSize="32" xml:space="preserve" Tag="__312">67 </Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="14" Tag="__312">West of</Run>
        <Run Tag="__312"> Embassy Row, all was silent again inside the walled garden with its twelfth-century roses and Shadow House gazebo. On the other side of an entry road, the young man was helping his hunched superior walk across an expansive lawn.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__312">He&#x2019;s letting me guide him?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__312">Normally, the blind old man refused help, preferring to navigate by memory alone while on the grounds of his sanctuary. Tonight, however, he was apparently in a hurry to get inside and return Warren Bellamy&#x2019;s phone call.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__312">&#x201C;Thank you,&#x201D; the old man said as they entered the building that held his private study. &#x201C;I can find my way from here.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__312">&#x201C;Sir, I would be happy to stay and help&#x2014;&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__312">&#x201C;That&#x2019;s all for tonight,&#x201D; he said, letting go of his helper&#x2019;s arm and shuffling hurriedly off into the darkness. &#x201C;Good night.&#x201D;</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__312">The young man exited the building and walked back across the great lawn to his modest dwelling on the grounds. By the time he entered his flat, he could feel his curiosity gnawing at him. The old man clearly had been upset by the question posed by Mr. Bellamy . . . and yet the question had seemed strange, almost meaningless.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__312">Is there no help for the widow&#x2019;s son?</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__312">In his wildest imagination, he could not guess what this could mean. Puzzled, he went to his computer and typed in a search for this precise phrase.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__312">To his great surprise, page after page of references appeared, all citing this exact question. He read the information in wonderment. It seemed Warren Bellamy was not the first person in history to ask this strange question. These same words had been uttered centuries ago . . . by King Solomon as he mourned a murdered friend. The question was allegedly still spoken today by Masons, who used it as a kind of encoded cry for help. Warren Bellamy, it seemed, was sending a distress call to a fellow Mason.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
