<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section Margin="24,16,24,16" BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True">
    <Paragraph/>
    <Section Margin="0,0,0,0" Tag="OEBPS/Brow_9780385533133_epub_c81_r1.htm#c81">
      <Paragraph Margin="0,17,0,18" TextAlignment="Right" FontFamily="sans-serif" FontSize="19">
        <Run FontFamily="sans-serif" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="19" Tag="__365">CHAPTER</Run>
        <Run FontFamily="sans-serif" FontSize="32" xml:space="preserve" Tag="__365">81 </Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="0" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontWeight="Bold" FontSize="14" Tag="__365">The subterranean</Run>
        <Run Tag="__365"> space in which Mal&#x2019;akh performed the Art was ingeniously hidden. His home&#x2019;s basement, to those who entered, appeared quite normal&#x2014;a typical cellar with boiler, fuse box, woodpile, and a hodgepodge of storage. This visible cellar, however, was only a portion of Mal&#x2019;akh&#x2019;s underground space. A sizable area had been walled off for his clandestine practices.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__365">Mal&#x2019;akh&#x2019;s private work space was a suite of small rooms, each with a specialized purpose. The area&#x2019;s sole entrance was a steep ramp secretly accessible through his living room, making the area&#x2019;s discovery virtually impossible.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__365">Tonight, as Mal&#x2019;akh descended the ramp, the tattooed sigils and signs on his flesh seemed to come alive in the cerulean glow of his basement&#x2019;s specialized lighting. Moving into the bluish haze, he walked past several closed doors and headed directly for the largest room at the end of the corridor.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__365">The &#x201C;sanctum sanctorum,&#x201D; as Mal&#x2019;akh liked to call it, was a perfect twelve-foot square. </Run>
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__365">Twelve are the signs of the zodiac. Twelve are the hours of the day. Twelve are the gates of heaven.</Run>
        <Run Tag="__365"> In the center of the chamber was a stone table, a seven-by-seven square. </Run>
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__365">Seven are the seals of Revelation. Seven are the steps of the Temple.</Run>
        <Run Tag="__365"> Centered over the table hung a carefully calibrated light source that cycled through a spectrum of preordained colors, completing its cycle every six hours in accordance with the sacred Table of Planetary Hours. </Run>
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__365">The hour of Yanor is blue. The hour of Nasnia is red. The hour of Salam is white.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__365">Now was the hour of Caerra, meaning the light in the room had modulated to a soft purplish hue. Wearing only a silken loincloth wrapped around his buttocks and neutered sex organ, Mal&#x2019;akh began his preparations.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="OEBPS/Brow_9780385533133_epub_c81_r1.htm#page302">He carefully combined the suffumigation chemicals that he would later ignite to sanctify the air. Then he folded the virgin silk robe that he would eventually don in place of his loincloth. And finally, he purified a flask of water for the anointing of his offering. When he was done, he placed all of these prepared ingredients on a side table.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__365">Next he went to a shelf and retrieved a small ivory box, which he carried to the side table and placed with the other items. Although he was not yet ready to use it, he could not resist opening the lid and admiring this treasure.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__366">The knife.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__366">Inside the ivory box, nestled in a cradle of black velvet, shone the sacrificial knife that Mal&#x2019;akh had been saving for tonight. He had purchased it for $1.6 million on the Middle Eastern antiquities black market last year.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__366">The most famous knife in history.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__366">Unimaginably old and believed lost, this precious blade was made of iron, attached to a bone handle. Over the ages, it had been in the possession of countless powerful individuals. In recent decades, however, it had disappeared, languishing in a secret private collection. Mal&#x2019;akh had gone to enormous lengths to obtain it. The knife, he suspected, had not drawn blood for decades . . . possibly centuries. Tonight, this blade would again taste the power of the sacrifice for which it was honed.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__366">Mal&#x2019;akh gently lifted the knife from its cushioned compartment and reverently polished the blade with a silk cloth soaked in purified water. His skills had progressed greatly since his first rudimentary experiments in New York. The dark Art that Mal&#x2019;akh practiced had been known by many names in many languages, but by any name, it was a precise science. This primeval technology had once held the key to the portals of power, but it had been banished long ago, relegated to the shadows of occultism and magic. Those few who still practiced this Art were considered madmen, but Mal&#x2019;akh knew better. </Run>
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__366">This is not work for those with dull faculties.</Run>
        <Run Tag="__366"> The ancient dark Art, like modern science, was a discipline involving precise formulas, specific ingredients, and meticulous timing.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__366">This Art was not the impotent black magic of today, often practiced halfheartedly by curious souls. This Art, like nuclear physics, had the potential to unleash enormous power. The warnings were dire: </Run>
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__366">The unskilled practitioner runs the risk of being struck by a reflux current and destroyed.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__366">Mal&#x2019;akh finished admiring the sacred blade and turned his attention to a lone sheet of thick vellum lying on the table before him. He had made this vellum himself from the skin of a baby lamb. As was the protocol, the lamb was pure, having not yet reached sexual maturity. Beside the vellum was a quill pen he had made from the feather of a crow, a silver saucer, and three glimmering candles arranged around a solid-brass bowl. The bowl contained one inch of thick crimson liquid.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph/>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__367">The liquid was Peter Solomon&#x2019;s blood.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__367">Blood is the tincture of eternity.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__367">Mal&#x2019;akh picked up the quill pen, placed his left hand on the vellum, and dipping the quill tip in the blood, he carefully traced the outline of his open palm. When he was done, he added the five symbols of the Ancient Mysteries, one on each fingertip of the drawing.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__367">The crown . . . to represent the king I shall become.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__367">The star . . . to represent the heavens which have ordained my destiny.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__367">The sun . . . to represent the illumination of my soul.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__367">The lantern . . . to represent the feeble light of human understanding.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__367">And the key . . . to represent the missing piece, that which tonight I shall at last possess.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__367">Mal&#x2019;akh completed his blood tracing and held up the vellum, admiring his work in the light of the three candles. He waited until the blood was dry and then folded the thick vellum three times. While chanting an ethereal ancient incantation, Mal&#x2019;akh touched the vellum to the third candle, and it burst into flames. He set the flaming vellum on the silver saucer and let it burn. As it did, the carbon in the animal skin dissolved to a powdery black char. When the flame went out, Mal&#x2019;akh carefully tapped the ashes into the brass bowl of blood. Then he stirred the mixture with the crow&#x2019;s feather.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__367">The liquid turned a deeper crimson, nearly black.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,17,0,12" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="serif" FontSize="14">
        <Run Tag="__367">Holding the bowl in both palms, Mal&#x2019;akh raised it over his head and gave thanks, intoning the blood </Run>
        <Run FontFamily="serif" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="14" Tag="__367">eukharistos</Run>
        <Run Tag="__367"> of the ancients. Then he carefully poured the blackened mixture into a glass vial and corked it. This would be the ink with which Mal&#x2019;akh would inscribe the untattooed flesh atop his head and complete his masterpiece.</Run>
      </Paragraph>
    </Section>
  </Section>
</Flow>
