<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Flow xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation" FontFamily="Garamond">
  <Section Margin="16,16,32,0" BreakPageBefore="True" BreakColumnBefore="True" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,56" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontWeight="Normal" FontSize="19">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page48" xml:space="preserve"/>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page49" xml:space="preserve"/>
      <Image Source="/Resources/7e50a363-a5c5-4faf-994a-583a47886c83.jpg" Stretch="Uniform" Width="186" Height="97" RenderOptions.BitmapScalingMode="NearestNeighbor"/>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__28">February 2008</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Figure HorizontalAnchor="ColumnLeft" HorizontalOffset="16" VerticalOffset="0" CanDelayPlacement="False" Height="42.6318367346939" Margin="0,0,1,0" Padding="0,0,0,0" TextAlignment="Justify" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="50" Tag="KNFBDropCap">
        <Paragraph LineHeight="50" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight">
          <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="50" Tag="__28">W</Run>
        </Paragraph>
      </Figure>
      <Run Tag="__28">ith Mona, I&#x2019;d lose all track of time while strolling along Hayle Avenue. Sometimes we pressed our noses so long against the front window of our favorite shop that the evening clothes disappeared behind the steamed-up glass. The white wedding dress on a plastic mannequin always caught my fancy. A dress for a lady! And what a contrast with all those women in the street, draped from head to toe in black.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__28">&#x201C;</Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__28">Insha&#x2019;Allah</Run>
      <Run Tag="__28">, God willing, you&#x2019;ll have one like this the day of your wedding,&#x201D; Mona would whisper, her sparkling eyes framed by the </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__28">niqab</Run>
      <Run Tag="__28"> that covered the rest of her face whenever she left the house.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page50">Mona rarely smiled. Fate had not smiled on her with a joyous wedding. Married in a hurry, she&#x2019;d had to make do with a blue dress, and aside from that detail, she was always evasive about the circumstances of her marriage. Ever since her husband had abruptly disappeared to who knows where, it had become a closed subject. I imagined he was traveling somewhere, far away from Yemen, but I was careful not to ask a single question. If I did, Mona would simply murmur that all she wanted for me was that I be happy and wind up with an affectionate and respectful husband.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__28">I would never have imagined that my wedding day would arrive so quickly.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__28">And anyway, I didn&#x2019;t have a really clear idea of what marriage was. To me, it was a big celebration most of all, with lots of presents, and chocolate, and jewelry. A new house, a new life! A few years earlier, I&#x2019;d attended various celebrations held for some distant boy and girl cousins, where there was music and dancing. Beneath their </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__28">balto</Run>
      <Run Tag="__28">s, their long black coats, the women were elegantly dressed. Their faces were exquisitely made up, their tresses smoothed by the hairdresser, like the pictures on bottles of shampoo, with little butterfly barrettes in the bangs of the most coquettish girls. I always had great fun at those parties. I remember the henna decorations on the hands and arms of the young brides, with designs like flowers. It was so beautiful, the henna. And I would think, </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__28">One day I&#x2019;ll have henna on my hands, too</Run>
      <Run Tag="__28">.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,16,0,16" TextAlignment="Center" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Image Source="/Resources/55832ac8-9b14-444c-baf4-73342eb8a897.jpg" Stretch="Uniform" Width="60" Height="20" RenderOptions.BitmapScalingMode="NearestNeighbor"/>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__29">The news came out of nowhere. When Aba informed me that my turn had come, I didn&#x2019;t really understand. At first I felt almost relieved, as if marriage were an escape hatch, because life at home had become impossible. Aba had never been able to find full-time employment after losing his street-sweeper job, so we were always late with the rent, and the landlord regularly threatened to evict us.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__29">To save money, Omma now cooked only rice and vegetable stews. She had begun teaching me how to help her with the household duties. We baked </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__29">shafout</Run>
      <Run Tag="__29">, a kind of large pancake slathered with yogurt flavored with garlic and onion, and </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__29">bint al-sahn</Run>
      <Run Tag="__29">, a delicious dessert prepared with honey. When my father brought home enough money, Omma would send one of my brothers out to buy a chicken she would cook for Friday, the Muslim holy day. Red meat? Forget it&#x2014;too expensive. In fact, I hadn&#x2019;t had any </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__29">fatah</Run>
      <Run Tag="__29">, beef stew, since my first-ever meal in a restaurant, where some cousins had invited us to celebrate Eid. We&#x2019;d even been allowed to drink some &#x201C;Bebsi,&#x201D; a black soda from America. And when we left the restaurant, a waiter sprinkled the grown-ups&#x2019; hands with perfume&#x2014;and mine, too! It smelled wonderful.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page52">Omma had also taught me to bake flatbread. She used to light the fire while I kneaded the dough, which she would then spread into the shape of a full moon before pressing it against the inner wall of the tandoor oven. One day, though, she had to relinquish her tandoor in exchange for a little money on the black market. Each time our purse was empty, she would sell a few of our possessions. Basically, she had given up relying on my father.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page53">And then came the day when there wasn&#x2019;t much left to sell. After they&#x2019;d missed enough meals for want of money, my brothers finally joined the young street vendors who tap on car windshields at red lights, hoping to trade a packet of facial tissues or some chewing gum for a few coins. Even Mona joined them, but begging played some mean tricks on her. Within twenty-four hours she was picked up by the police and sent off to a detention center. When she returned home, she told us she&#x2019;d found herself among ladies accused of going with several men at the same time, and that the women guards in the prison pulled everyone&#x2019;s hair. When she had gotten over her fright, she went out again to beg and wound up once more nose to nose with the police. After that second incarceration, she gave up her risky escapades. Then it was Ha&#xEF;fa&#x2019;s and my turn to try it. Hand in hand, we went out to scratch our nails on car windows, barely daring even to glance at the drivers, who quite often ignored us. I didn&#x2019;t like that, but we had no choice.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__30">On days when Aba didn&#x2019;t lie too long in bed, he left home to go crouch on his heels like the other jobless men on one of the public squares in the neighborhood, hoping to land a day&#x2019;s work as a laborer, mason, or handyman for a thousand or so rials&#x2014;about five dollars. More and more often now, he was spending his afternoons chewing khat with some neighbors. He claimed it helped him forget his troubles, and this routine had become a ritual. Sitting cross-legged with the other local men, he would select the best green leaves from a small plastic bag and tuck them into a corner of his mouth. The emptier the bag became, the more swollen his cheek grew, until the leaves formed a ball he would chew for hours and hours.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__30">It was during one of those khat sessions that a man of about thirty had approached him.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__30">&#x201C;I would like our two families to be united,&#x201D; the man had said.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page54">His name was Faez Ali Thamer, and he worked as a deliveryman, carrying packages everywhere on his motorcycle. Like us, he was originally from the village of Khardji, and he was looking for a wife. My father accepted his proposal immediately. As the next in line after my two big sisters Jamila and Mona, I was the logical one to be married off. When Aba returned home, his mind was already made up. And no one could change it.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">That very evening, I overheard a conversation between Mona and our father.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">&#x201C;Nujood is way too young to get married,&#x201D; Mona insisted.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts8a">&#x201C;</Run>
      <Hyperlink NavigateUri="Ali_9780307589682_epub_nts_r1.htm#nts8">
        <Hyperlink.TextDecorations>
          <TextDecorationCollection/>
        </Hyperlink.TextDecorations>
        <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts8a">Too young? When the prophet</Run>
      </Hyperlink>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts8a"> Mohammad wed A&#xEF;sha, she was only nine years old,&#x201D; replied Aba.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">&#x201C;Yes, but that was in the time of the Prophet. Now things are different.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">&#x201C;Listen&#x2014;this marriage, it&#x2019;s the best way to protect her.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">&#x201C;What do you mean by that?&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">&#x201C;You know perfectly well. She will be spared the same problems you and Jamila had. This way she won&#x2019;t be raped by a stranger and become the prey of evil rumors. This man seems honest, at least. He&#x2019;s known in the neighborhood. He comes from our village. And he has promised not to touch Nujood until she&#x2019;s older.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">&#x201C;But&#x2014;&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page55">&#x201C;I&#x2019;ve made my decision! Besides, you know we haven&#x2019;t enough money to feed the whole family. So this will mean one less mouth.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">My mother never said a thing. She seemed sad, but resigned. After all, she had wed through an arranged marriage, like most Yemeni women, so she was in a good position to know that in our country it&#x2019;s the men who give the orders, and the women who follow them. For her to defend me was a waste of time.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__31">I kept hearing my father&#x2019;s words in my mind: </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__31">one less mouth</Run>
      <Run Tag="__31">. So that&#x2019;s all I was to him, a burden, and he had seized the first chance to get rid of me. It was true that I hadn&#x2019;t always been the good little girl he would have liked to have, but after all, isn&#x2019;t getting into mischief part of being a child? And I loved him in spite of his faults, and that nasty smell of khat, and his insistence that we go beg for a few crusts of bread in the street.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page56">The same problems you and Jamila had</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page56">. What did he mean by that? All I knew was that a week had gone by, then another, and another, and Jamila had not come back. Like Mona&#x2019;s husband, she had abruptly vanished. I had even given up keeping track of how many days I had gone without seeing her. She used to visit us so often, and now she had simply disappeared. I was quite fond of Jamila. Every once in a while, she had brought me sweets; although she was shy and not very talkative, she was thoughtful and generous. And Mona&#x2019;s husband had never come back after his mysterious disappearance, either. Where had he gone? Grown-ups and their affairs were too complicated for me.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__32">After her son vanished, Mona&#x2019;s mother-in-law had demanded custody of her grandchildren, three-year-old Monira and eighteen-month-old Nasser. Heartsick, Mona had fought like a tigress to keep her children, and her tenacity had brought her a partial victory: pleading the necessity of nursing her baby son, she managed to hold on to him. Now, haunted by the thought of losing him, she never took her eyes off him. Whenever he wandered off, she ran to catch him up in her arms, holding him tight as if he were a treasure she were trying to hide.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__32">My wedding preparations moved rapidly ahead, and I soon realized my misfortune when my future husband&#x2019;s family decided that I must leave school a month before the wedding night. I hugged Malak sadly, promising her that I would soon be back.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page57">&#x201C;One day, we&#x2019;ll go together to the seashore,&#x201D; she murmured, holding me close.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__32">That was the last time I ever saw her.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__32">I had to say good-bye as well to my two favorite teachers, Samia and Samira. With them, I had learned to write my first name in Arabic letters, from right to left: the curve of the </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__32">noon</Run>
      <Run Tag="__32">, the sway of the </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__32">jeem</Run>
      <Run Tag="__32">, the loop of the </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__32">wow</Run>
      <Run Tag="__32">, and the pincers of the </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__32">del</Run>
      <Run Tag="__32">: Nujood! I owed them so much.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__33">Mathematics and Koran study were two of my favorite subjects. We had memorized the Five Pillars of Islam in class: the </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__33">shahada</Run>
      <Run Tag="__33">, or profession of faith; </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__33">salat</Run>
      <Run Tag="__33">, prayer for guidance; the </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__33">hajj</Run>
      <Run Tag="__33">, the great pilgrimage to Mecca; </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__33">zakat</Run>
      <Run Tag="__33">, alms to the poor; and Ramadan, the monthlong fast during which Muslims neither eat nor drink from sunrise to sunset. My classmates and I had promised Samia that when we were older, we would observe Ramadan like the grown-ups did.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__33">My favorite subject, though, was drawing. With my colored pencils I used to draw flowers and pears, and villas with blue roofs, green shutters, and red chimneys. Sometimes I would add a uniformed guard to stand in front of the entrance gate because I&#x2019;d heard that rich people&#x2019;s houses were protected by guards. I always drew big fruit trees in the garden. Plus a pretty little pond, right in the middle.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page58">During recess we played hide-and-seek and recited nursery rhymes. I loved school. It was my refuge, a happiness all my own.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__33">I also had to give up my escapades at our next-door neighbors&#x2019; house, only a few yards from ours, where they had a transistor radio. My little sister Ha&#xEF;fa and I had taken to visiting them to listen to tapes by Ha&#xEF;fa Wehbe and Nancy Ajram, two beautiful Lebanese singers with long hair and heavy makeup. They had lovely eyes and perfect noses; we used to imitate them, batting our eyelids and wiggling our hips. We also liked the Yemeni singer Jamila Saad, who was a real star. &#x201C;You think so much of yourself,&#x201D; she warbled in one of her love songs, &#x201C;You think you&#x2019;re simply the best.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__33">The people next door were also among the few in the neighborhood lucky enough to have a tele vision. The TV was my ticket to travel. I adored watching </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__33">Tom and Jerry</Run>
      <Run Tag="__33">, my favorite cartoon, and a show called </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__33">Adnan and Lina</Run>
      <Run Tag="__33">, which told the story of two friends who had met on a far-off island. I think they were supposed to be Japanese, or maybe Chinese, but the amazing thing was that they spoke Arabic, just like me, and without an accent. Adnan was a brave boy who was always ready to save Lina; in fact, he saved her repeatedly from bad people who tried to kidnap her. She was so lucky! I envied her a lot.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page59">Adnan reminded me of Eyman, a young boy from Al-Qa I will never forget. One day when I was walking in the street with some of my girlfriends, a neighborhood boy stopped us and started frightening us, saying nasty things that seemed insulting. He was laughing at our scared expressions when Eyman appeared like magic to challenge him.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__34">&#x201C;Get out or I&#x2019;ll throw stones in your face!&#x201D; Eyman told him.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__34">When Eyman&#x2019;s threat finally drove the boy away, it was such a relief. That was the only time anyone had ever come to my defense, and Eyman became my imaginary hero. I told myself that when I was grown up, maybe I&#x2019;d be lucky enough to have a husband like him.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page60">On my wedding day, my female cousins began to ululate and clap their hands when they caught sight of me arriving. I, however, could hardly see their faces, my eyes were so full of tears. I advanced slowly, doing my best to avoid tripping over my outfit, which was too big for me and dragged on the ground. I&#x2019;d been hastily dressed in a long tunic of a faded chocolate color, which belonged to the wife of my future brother-in-law. A female relative had taken charge of my hair, which she gathered into a chignon that weighed down my head. I didn&#x2019;t even get to wear any mascara. Catching sight of my face in a small mirror&#x2014;round cheeks, pink lips, and brown, almond-shaped eyes&#x2014;I&#x2019;d noticed how smooth my brow was, and try as I might, I couldn&#x2019;t find a single wrinkle. I was young, too young.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page61">Barely two weeks had passed since I had been spoken for. Following local custom, the women celebrated my wedding in my parents&#x2019; tiny house; there were forty of us, all told. Meanwhile, the men gathered at the house of one of my uncles to celebrate, and to chew khat yet again. Two days earlier, when the marriage contract had been signed, the event had also been men only, and occurred behind closed doors. Everything had happened without me. Neither my mother, my sisters, nor I had had any right to know how things had gone. We found out the details late that afternoon only through my little brothers, who had gone off to beg a few coins in the street to pay for refreshments for my father, my uncle, and my future husband, along with his father and brother. We learned that the meeting had taken place according to well-established tribal protocol. My father&#x2019;s brother-in-law, the only one present who could read and write, acted as notary, drawing up the marriage contract. My dowry had been set at 150,000 rials, a sum equivalent to 750 dollars.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__35">&#x201C;Don&#x2019;t worry,&#x201D; I heard my father whisper to my mother that night. &#x201C;They made him promise not to touch Nujood before the year after she has her first period.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__35">I shuddered.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__35">My wedding celebration, which began at lunchtime, was quickly over. No white dress. No henna flowers on my hands. No coconut candies, my absolute favorites, the ones that hold the sweet taste of happy days. It was over quickly&#x2014;but to me it seemed to last forever. Sitting in a corner of the room, I refused to dance with the other women because I was gradually realizing that my life was undergoing a complete upheaval, and not for the better. The youngest women began to improvise a belly dance, baring their navels and undulating their bodies like something out of a tacky video. Holding hands, the older women performed more traditional folk dances, like the ones still seen in villages. During lulls in the music, they came over to greet me, and I embraced them dutifully. But I couldn&#x2019;t even pretend to smile.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page62">I just sat impassively in my corner of the main room, my face swollen from crying. I didn&#x2019;t want to leave my family. I didn&#x2019;t feel prepared. I already missed school painfully, and Malak even more. Catching sight of my little sister Ha&#xEF;fa&#x2019;s sad face during the celebration, I realized with a pang that I would miss her as well. I felt a sudden rush of fear: What if she, too, were condemned to suffer my fate?</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__36">At sundown the guests took their leave and I dozed off, fully clothed, Ha&#xEF;fa at my side. My mother joined us a little later, after straightening up the room. When my father returned from his all-male meeting, we were fast asleep. During my last night in my parents&#x2019; house, no dreams came to me, nor do I remember sleeping fitfully. I only wondered if I would awaken the next morning as if from a nightmare.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page63">When sunlight flooded the room at around six o&#x2019;clock the next morning, Omma woke me up and asked me to follow her out into the narrow hallway. As we did each morning, we bowed down before God, reciting the first prayer of the day. Then she served me a bowl of </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page63">ful</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page63"> (fava beans cooked with onions and tomato sauce, which we eat at breakfast) and a cup of milky </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page63">cha&#xEF;</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page63">, our tea. My little bundle was waiting for me in front of our door, but I pretended not to see it. It was only when a car horn sounded outside the house that I was forced to resign myself to this new life full of uncertainty. After hugging me tightly, my mother helped me cover myself in a black coat and scarf. For the past few years I had worn simply a small colored veil when I went outside, and sometimes I even forgot it, but no one ever paid any attention. Now I saw Omma reach into my bundle and pull out a black </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page63">niqab</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page63">, which she handed to me. Never, until that moment, had I been forced to veil myself completely.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__36">&#x201C;From this day on, you must cover yourself when going out into the street. You are now a married woman. Your face must be seen by no one but your husband. Because it is his </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__36">sharaf</Run>
      <Run Tag="__36">, his honor, that is at stake. And you must not disgrace it.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__36">I nodded sadly and said good-bye to her. I was angry at Omma for abandoning me, but could find no words to tell her of my pain.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page64">In the back of the SUV waiting in front of our door, a short man was staring at me. He wore a long white </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page64">zanna</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page64">, like Aba, and had a mustache. His short wavy hair was somewhat mussed, his eyes brown, and his face poorly shaved. His hands were stained with black grease. He was not handsome. So this was Faez Ali Thamer! The man who had asked for and been granted my hand, that stranger whom I had perhaps walked past one day in Khardji&#x2014;where we had returned for visits several times over the last few years&#x2014;but whom I did not remember.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__37">They had me sit in the middle row of seats, right behind the driver, with four other female passengers, including the wife of my husband&#x2019;s brother. Their smiles were strained, and they didn&#x2019;t seem very talkative. The stranger sat all the way in the back, next to his brother. I felt a little better not having to look at his face during our long ride, but I could feel his eyes on me, and it gave me the shivers. Who was he, actually? Why had he wanted to marry me? What was he expecting of me? And marriage&#x2014;what exactly did that mean? I had no answers to those questions.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__37">When the motor rumbled to life and the driver pulled away, my heart was pounding, and I couldn&#x2019;t help myself&#x2014;I started crying, silently, with my face glued to the window as I watched Omma grow smaller and smaller until she was only a tiny little dot of nothing at all.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page65">I never said a word that whole trip. Lost in my thoughts, I wanted only one thing: to find a way to go back home, to escape. The farther away from Sana&#x2019;a the car drove on its way north, however, the more I understood how trapped I was. How many times did I wish I could tear off that stifling black </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page65">niqab</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page65">? I felt so small, too small for this whole business&#x2014;for the </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page65">niqab</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page65">, for this long ride far away from my parents, for this new life beside a man who disgusted me, a man I didn&#x2019;t know. The vehicle stopped suddenly.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__37">&#x201C;Open the back door!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts9a">The soldier&#x2019;s voice startled me. Exhausted from too much crying, I had finally fallen asleep. Then I remembered that the road north is full of checkpoints, and that we were only at the first one. People say it&#x2019;s because of the war raging in the north between the army and </Run>
      <Hyperlink NavigateUri="Ali_9780307589682_epub_nts_r1.htm#nts9">
        <Hyperlink.TextDecorations>
          <TextDecorationCollection/>
        </Hyperlink.TextDecorations>
        <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts9a">the Houthi rebels</Run>
      </Hyperlink>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts9a">; my father says that the Houthis are Shiites, while most Yemenis are Sunnis. The difference? I have no idea. All I know is that I am Muslim and recite my five daily prayers.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__38">After a glance inside the vehicle, the soldier sent us on our way. If only I could have taken that moment to appeal for his help, to ask him to save me! With his green uniform, his weapon on his shoulder, wasn&#x2019;t he supposed to ensure order and public safety? Then I could have told him that I didn&#x2019;t want to leave Sana&#x2019;a, that I was afraid of being bored and alone out in that village, where I didn&#x2019;t know anyone anymore.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page66">Over the years I&#x2019;d grown used to Sana&#x2019;a. I loved all the buildings under construction in the capital, the wide avenues, the billboard advertisements for cell phones and orange sodas that tickled the roof of my mouth. Pollution and traffic jams had become part of my daily life. But it was the old city, Bab al-Yemen&#x2014;Yemen&#x2019;s Gate&#x2014;that I would miss the most. Bab al-Yemen is truly a city within the city, a magical place where I loved to stroll around, holding Mona&#x2019;s or Jamila&#x2019;s hand, feeling as if I were an explorer off on a mission. It&#x2019;s a whole different universe, with its adobe houses and windows outlined in white tracery so delicate that Indian architects must clearly have passed through there long ago, well before my time. Bab al-Yemen is so elegantly civilized that I&#x2019;d invented my own story of a king and queen from the olden days who must have lived out happy lives there. Perhaps the old city had even belonged entirely to them?</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page67">Anyone who enters Bab al-Yemen is immediately surrounded by all sorts of sounds: merchants&#x2019; cries mingle with the popping and hissing of old cassette tapes and the laments of barefoot beggars, while a shoeshine boy at an intersection might grab your foot to offer you his services. The call to prayer often rises above this entire concert of jumbled noises. I used to have fun trying to sniff out the different smells of cumin, cinnamon, cloves, nuts, raisins&#x2014;all the scents wafting from the street booths. Sometimes I would stand on tiptoe to better appreciate the goods laid out in stalls that were a little too high for me, but whose bounty lay heaped up as far as the eye could see: silver </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page67">jambia</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page67">s, embroidered shawls, rugs, sugared doughnuts, henna, and dresses for little girls my age.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts10a">In Bab al-Yemen, we&#x2019;d sometimes see women draped in </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts10a">sitara</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts10a">s (&#x201C;curtains&#x201D; in Arabic), large, colorful pieces of beautifully patterned cloth worn over their clothes. I used to call them &#x201C;the ladies of the old city&#x201D; because their brightly colored outfits were just so different from </Run>
      <Hyperlink NavigateUri="Ali_9780307589682_epub_nts_r1.htm#nts10">
        <Hyperlink.TextDecorations>
          <TextDecorationCollection/>
        </Hyperlink.TextDecorations>
        <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts10a">the black veils usually worn</Run>
      </Hyperlink>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#nts10a"> in the street that these women seemed to belong to another age.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__39">One afternoon, when I was accompanying my aunt on some errands, I allowed myself to be distracted by this fantastic and almost unreal world, and I wandered off into the middle of the dense crowd. When I tried to retrace my steps to rejoin my aunt, I found that all the lanes and alleys looked alike. Should I take the next one on the right, or on the left? Disoriented, I crouched down in tears: I was well and truly lost. And it was only two hours later that I was spotted by a vendor who knew my aunt.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__39">&#x201C;Nujood, when will you stop being so scatterbrained?&#x201D; Auntie had scolded me, grabbing my hand.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page68">And here I was, lost again, on this sad day after my wedding, sitting in the uncomfortable SUV, only now the people around me were grim and unfriendly. Gone were the magic of spices and the kindly looks of vendors who let children taste their still-warm doughnuts. My life was taking a new turn in this world of grown-ups, where dreams no longer had a place, faces became masks, and no one seemed to care about me.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__39">Once the capital was behind us, the highway became a black ribbon snaking along among mountains and valleys. At every turn I clutched the armrest of my seat. My stomach was heaving, and several times I had to pinch myself, hard, to control my nausea. Better to die than to ask </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__39">him</Run>
      <Run Tag="__39"> to stop by the roadside so that I could breathe some fresh air, I thought. I kept gently swallowing my saliva as quietly as possible, trying not to be sick.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page69">To block out everyone around me, I decided to observe the smallest details of the landscape. There were old fortresses in ruins perched on promontories; little brown houses with white trim that vaguely reminded me of Bab al-Yemen; cacti by the side of the road; arid mountain passes alternating with pockets of agriculture; goats cropping the grass; and cows. There were women, too, their faces partly hidden by the scarves they pulled over their mouths. I thought I also saw two run-over cats, but I closed my eyes quickly to avoid memorizing the image. When I opened them again, the car was driving through an ocean of khat. On the right, on the left, green as far as I could see. It was magnificent, so fresh and cool.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__40">&#x201C;Khat, our national tragedy!&#x201D; exclaimed the driver. &#x201C;It sucks up so much water that we&#x2019;ll all wind up dying of thirst in this country.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__40">Life is really weird</Run>
      <Run Tag="__40">, I thought. </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__40">It&#x2019;s not just bad people who spread misery&#x2014;even pretty things can be hurtful. So hard to understand &#x2026;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__40">A little farther along, to my right, I recognized Cocabane, a small village cut into the living rock, way up atop a hill. I remembered going by the place with my parents when I was younger, on our way to another village to celebrate Eid. People say the women of Cocabane are thin and beautiful because they go every morning to labor in the fields. An hour to walk down, another to climb back up&#x2014;a real workout. What courage! </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__40">An hour to walk down &#x2026; another to climb back up. An hour to walk down &#x2026;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__40">It was the throbbing of the car&#x2019;s engine that woke me with a start. How long had I been asleep? How many miles had we driven? I had no idea.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page70">&#x201C;One, two, three!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__40">Behind the vehicle, a half-dozen men were pushing on the bumper with all their strength, trying to free us from a sandy hole. Amid the dust cloud raised by the wheels, I tried to read the sign bearing the name of the dried-up village where we had run aground. Arjom. Apparently we had left the highway for a rocky, rutted road edging a ravine that led to a deep gorge. The car was definitely at a standstill.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__41">&#x201C;You&#x2019;d do better to turn around,&#x201D; one of the villagers suggested. He had a red and white headcloth wrapped around his face. &#x201C;You&#x2019;ll never get any farther; this track just keeps getting worse.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__41">&#x201C;But we must get to Khardji,&#x201D; insisted the driver.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__41">&#x201C;Pfft&#x2014;with your car? You&#x2019;re joking.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__41">&#x201C;Well, then, how?&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__41">&#x201C;The best way is to go by donkey.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__41">&#x201C;Riding donkeys! But there are women with us. It might be difficult.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__41">&#x201C;Listen, why not hire one of our fellows? He&#x2019;s used to making round-trips carrying visitors. And the tires on his car are up to it&#x2014;he gets new ones at least every two months, the road&#x2019;s so bad.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page71">So we changed cars, and while the grown-ups were busy moving our bundles into the other one, I used those few minutes to stretch my legs. I took a deep breath, drawing as much pure mountain air into my lungs as possible. Below my black veil, the brown dress was sticking to my skin with perspiration, and I picked up the folds of material to go carefully over to the edge of the ravine. Right at the bottom, so far away, I recognized Wadi La&#x2019;a, the valley of my village&#x2014;it hadn&#x2019;t changed. I&#x2019;d been so little, though, when we&#x2019;d left. Were my childhood memories coming back, kept alive thanks to a few recent trips to the area with my parents? Or was I recalling things from the faded photographs languishing in an old album that Aba looked at from time to time with tears in his eyes? I saw my grandfather again in my mind&#x2019;s eye, my Jad, whom I had loved so much. It had been a year since his death, when I had cried and cried. He always wore a white turban, and although his beard was thin and grizzled, he had bushy, dark brown eyebrows. Sometimes he would sit me on his knees and playfully tip me over backward, then catch me at the last minute. I&#x2019;d grown used to the idea that if the world collapsed around me, my Jad would always be there to save me. He had gone too soon.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__42">&#x201C;Nujood! Nujood!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page72">I turned around, wondering who could be calling me in that unfamiliar voice, so strange to my ears. Not like Jad&#x2019;s, a voice I could always recognize with my eyes closed. Looking up, I realized that it was </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page72">him</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page72">, my unknown husband, speaking to me for the first time since we&#x2019;d left Sana&#x2019;a. With barely a glance at me, he announced that it was time to leave again. Nodding, I headed toward our new &#x201C;carriage&#x201D;: a rusted-out red and white Toyota pickup. I was put in the front seat with the veiled sister-in-law, sitting on the new driver&#x2019;s right. The men clambered into the open truck bed in the back, with other passengers who were catching a ride.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__42">&#x201C;Hang on tight,&#x201D; warned the driver. &#x201C;The pickup will rock back and forth.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__42">Before setting out, he turned on his tape deck at top volume, and folk music began crackling out of loudspeakers as rusty as the pickup. The vibrations of the oud, a kind of Oriental lute, accompanied the voice of a very well-known local singer, Hussein Moheb, and soon they were joined by the jolting of the pickup doing battle with the big stones in the road. We weren&#x2019;t rocking back and forth, though; we were flying in all directions! Several times, stones crashed into our windshield, and I hung on for dear life, praying to arrive at the village in one piece.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__42">&#x201C;Listen to the music, it will make you forget your fear!&#x201D; shouted the driver.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page73">If he had only known what other fears tormented me.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__42">Hour after hour we drove, to the sound of Hussein Moheb&#x2019;s wailing; I should have counted the number of times the driver rewound the cassette. He seemed intoxicated by the music, which surely gave him the courage to forge ahead. Hanging on to his steering wheel like a rider clinging to his horse, he tackled even the slightest turn with his eyes riveted on the winding road, as if he knew all its pitfalls by heart.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__43">&#x201C;God made nature tough, but luckily he made men even tougher!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__43">Well</Run>
      <Run Tag="__43">, I thought, </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__43">if the driver is right, then God must have forgotten to include me</Run>
      <Run Tag="__43">.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__43">The deeper into the valley we went, the worse I felt. I was tired. I felt sick to my stomach. I was hungry and thirsty. But most of all, I was afraid. The closer we came to Wadi La&#x2019;a, the more uncertain my fate seemed. And my hopes for escape? Dashed.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page74">Khardji hadn&#x2019;t changed; it still felt like the end of the earth. As soon as we arrived, aching from the bone-jarring ride, I recognized the five stone houses, the modest river flowing through the village, the bees humming from flower to flower, the endless trees, and the village children going to the well to fill their little yellow jerry cans. A woman was waiting for us on the threshold of one of the houses. I felt immediately that she didn&#x2019;t like me. She didn&#x2019;t embrace me&#x2014;not even a tiny kiss, not even a gentle pat. </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page74">His</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page74"> mother. My new mother-in-law. She was old and ugly, with skin as wrinkled as a lizard&#x2019;s. She was missing two of her front teeth, while the others were rotten from cavities and blackened by tobacco. She wore a black and gray head scarf. She gestured for me to enter. The inside of the house was spare, with hardly any furnishings: four bedrooms, a living room, a tiny kitchen. The toilet was out under the stars, behind some bushes.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__43">I hadn&#x2019;t eaten anything since we&#x2019;d left Sana&#x2019;a; I was famished and fairly fell upon the rice and meat that </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__43">his</Run>
      <Run Tag="__43"> sisters had prepared. Joined after our meal by some guests from the village, the grown-ups gathered to chew khat. Again! Huddled in a corner, I watched them in silence. To my astonishment, no one seemed surprised by my tender age. Later I learned that marriages to little girls are not unusual in the countryside, so for these people, I didn&#x2019;t seem like an exception. There is even a tribal proverb that says, &#x201C;To guarantee a happy marriage, marry a nine-year-old girl.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page75">The grown-ups were chatting up a storm.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__44">&#x201C;Life in Sana&#x2019;a has become so expensive,&#x201D; my sister-in-law was complaining.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__44">&#x201C;As of tomorrow, I&#x2019;m going to teach the child to work like the rest of us,&#x201D; announced my mother-in-law, without saying my name. &#x201C;And I certainly hope she brought some money with her.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__44">&#x201C;No more time for girlish fancies. We&#x2019;ll show her how to be a woman, a real one.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__44">I remember how relieved I felt when they led me to my room, after the guests had gone at sunset. That brown tunic I&#x2019;d been wearing since the day before was starting to smell really foul, and now I could finally take it off. Once the door had shut behind me, I sighed deeply and quickly slipped into a little red cotton shirt I&#x2019;d brought from Sana&#x2019;a. It smelled like home, a musty smell with a hint of resinous incense, a familiar and comforting scent. A long woven mat was lying on the floor: my bed. Beside it was an old oil lamp that cast the shadow of its flame on the wall. I didn&#x2019;t even need to put out the light to fall asleep.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph Margin="0,32,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page76">I would rather have never awakened. When the door crashed open, I was startled awake, and thought that the night wind must have come up unusually strong. I&#x2019;d barely opened my eyes when I felt a damp, hairy body pressing against me. Someone had blown out the lamp, leaving the room pitch dark. I shivered. It was </Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page76">him</Run>
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page76">! I recognized him right away from that overpowering odor of cigarettes and khat. He stank! Like an animal! Without a word, he began to rub himself against me.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__44">&#x201C;Please, I&#x2019;m begging you, leave me alone,&#x201D; I gasped. I was shaking.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__44">&#x201C;You are my wife! From now on, I decide everything. We must sleep in the same bed.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__44">I leapt to my feet, ready to run away. Where? What did it matter&#x2014;I had to escape from this trap. Then he stood up, too. The door was not completely closed, and spying a glimmer of light from the moon and stars, I dashed immediately toward the courtyard.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">He ran after me.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">&#x201C;Help! Help!&#x201D; I shrieked, sobbing.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">My voice rang in the night, but it was as if I were shouting into a void. I ran everywhere, anywhere, panting for breath. I went into one room but ducked out again when he followed me there. I ran without looking back. I stumbled over something, maybe a piece of glass, and scrambled to my feet to take off again, but arms caught me, held me tightly, wrestled me back into the bedroom, pushed me down on the mat. I felt paralyzed, as if I had been tied down.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page77">Hoping to find a female ally, I called out to my mother-in-law.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">&#x201C;</Run>
      <Run FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontStyle="Italic" FontSize="16" Tag="__45">Amma!</Run>
      <Run Tag="__45"> Auntie!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">There was no reply. I screamed again.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">&#x201C;Somebody help me!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">When he took off his white tunic, I rolled into a ball to protect myself, but he began pulling at my nightshirt, wanting me to undress. Then he ran his rough hands over my body and pressed his lips against mine. He smelled so awful, a mixture of tobacco and onion.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">I tried to get away again, moaning, &#x201C;Get away from me! I&#x2019;ll tell my father!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">&#x201C;You can tell your father whatever you like. He signed the marriage contract. He gave me permission to marry you.&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">&#x201C;You have no right!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">&#x201C;Nujood, you are my wife!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">&#x201C;Help! Help!&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">He started to laugh, nastily.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__45">&#x201C;I repeat: you are my wife. Now you must do what I want! Got that?&#x201D;</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="OEBPS/Ali_9780307589682_epub_c04_r1.htm#page78">Suddenly it was as if I&#x2019;d been snatched up by a hurricane, flung around, struck by lightning, and I had no more strength to fight back. There was a peal of thunder, and another, and another&#x2014;the sky was falling down on me, and it was then that something burning, a burning I had never felt before, invaded the deepest part of me. No matter how I screamed, no one came to help me. It hurt, awfully, and I was all alone to face the pain.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph TextIndent="16" Margin="0,4,0,4" TextAlignment="Justify" LineHeight="19" LineStackingStrategy="BlockLineHeight" FontFamily="Charis SIL" FontSize="16">
      <Run Tag="__46">With what felt like my last breath, I shrieked one more time, I think, and then lost consciousness.</Run>
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
</Flow>
